<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pests on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/categories/pests/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pests on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 11:14:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/categories/pests/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rat Mitigation Zones</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/rat-mitigation-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/rat-mitigation-zones/</guid>
      <description>Rats can contaminate food, spread disease and reduce our quality of life. Rat Mitigation Zones (RMZ) are areas with high levels of rat activity, where City agencies focus resources to address rats and the conditions that support them.&#xA;Choose an RMZ on the map below to view data on complaints and NYC Health Department rat control activity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why trash is a public health issue</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/sanitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 13:11:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/sanitation/</guid>
      <description>New York City’s modern history of public health starts in the 1600s with the Bureau of Sanitary Inspections, and ever since, sanitation has been an essential part of public health — fighting disease by keeping our city clean.&#xA;From A Chronology of the NYC Department of Health&#xA;How sanitation affects health Proper sanitation is a crucial component of public health and of safe, health, and equitable neighborhood environments.&#xA;Trash can pollute our soil, water, and air, becoming an issue of health, quality of life and equity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rat Information Portal</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/rat-information-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/rat-information-portal/</guid>
      <description>New York City’s Rat Information Portal is a web map application that lets you view rat inspection and action data collected by the NYC Health Department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.&#xA;Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bed bugs</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</guid>
      <description>Bed bugs are small insects that feed mainly on human blood. They are often confused with other insects, and many people are not even aware of their presence until they have been bitten. However, not everyone has a reaction to bed bug bites. You may not discover that you have bed bugs until you see other signs of the pests such as, bed bugs themselves, their eggs or droppings, or the blood stains they leave behind in mattresses, box springs, chairs or other materials.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cockroaches</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cockroaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cockroaches/</guid>
      <description>Cockroaches are a common urban pest. Though there are more than a thousand species of roaches, just a few are found in NYC homes. The most common are American Cockroaches, typically found in moist basements and lower floors, and German Cockroaches, found anywhere inside homes.&#xA;Cockroaches like warm, dark places such as toasters, clocks, microwave ovens, walls, and cabinets. They need regular access to food and water to live and breed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mice and rats</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</guid>
      <description>Rats and mice are common, but preventable. In NYC, rats tend to be seen on streets, alleys and sidewalks, and in yards and basements, while mice are almost always found inside buildings.&#xA;Rats and mice thrive where there are sources of food and shelter and where property owners fail to prevent and adequately respond to their presence.&#xA;Mice, Rats and Health Today, rats are recognized for their contribution to neighborhood stress, poor quality of life, contamination of food, potential threat to public health, and for their contribution to the destruction of infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pesticides</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/pesticides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/pesticides/</guid>
      <description>Pesticides are chemicals applied to kill or control insects, rats and mice, undesirable plants and weeds, or fungi (e.g., mold). Pesticides are often categorized by type of use (e.g., rodenticide, insecticide) or chemical class (e.g., organophosphate, pyrethroid).&#xA;Modern pesticides have been developed to have less persistence in the environment than earlier chlorine-based chemicals such as DDT. Pesticides may be applied by a commercial applicator or a non-professional who has purchased a product from a store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vector-borne disease</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</guid>
      <description>Vectorborne diseases are diseases that are transmitted from an arthropod (usually a tick or mosquito, etc.) to humans or other animals. Some vectorborne disease agents are maintained primarily through transmission between arthropods and humans (e.g., dengue virus and malaria), while others are maintained between arthropods and animal reservoirs (e.g., Lyme disease and West Nile virus) and humans may become infected incidentally.&#xA;Vectorborne Disease and the Environment Climate is one of many important interacting variables that affect people’s risk for vectorborne diseases in New York City.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pests and pesticides</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/pests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/pests/</guid>
      <description>Pests and pesticides can both have health effects. Household pests like mice, rats, and cockroaches can trigger asthma, while bed bugs are a well-known nuisance. Meanwhile, warmer winters may mean more vector-borne diseases like babesiosis and west nile virus.&#xA;Pesticides are chemicals used to control or kill insects, rats, mice, plants and weeds, or fungi (mold). Exposure to pesticides can occur from consuming foods or beverages that contain pesticide residues, from direct contact with the skin or eyes, or from breathing air in areas where pesticides are applied.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
