<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Explorer on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Explorer on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 09:34:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active Design</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/active-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/active-design/</guid>
      <description>Physical inactivity and unhealthy diet rank among the leading risk factors for premature death in the United States. Active design promotes health by using architectural and urban design strategies to encourage stair climbing, walking, bicycling, transit use, active recreation and healthy eating.
What we can do:
 Increase access to public parks and recreation. Create pedestrian plazas. Ensure well-maintained sidewalks. Plant street trees. Provide secure bicycle storage. Make stairways in buildings attractive and accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.
Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter andground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.
Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol Access</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-access/</guid>
      <description>Heavy regular drinking and binge drinking contribute to a wide range of chronic health problems, including heart disease, diabetes, cancer, stroke, cirrhosis, depression and dementia. Alcohol use is also associated with suicide, homicide, domestic violence, sexually transmitted diseases and injuries. It is one of the leading behavior-related causes of death in New York City (NYC).
This site provides data on heavy alcohol consumption and alcohol outlets in NYC.
Alcohol and the Environment Greater alcohol outlet density has been associated with a variety of health and social consequences, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol Use</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-use/</guid>
      <description>Heavy regular drinking and binge drinking contribute to a wide range of chronic health problems, including heart disease, diabetes, cancer, stroke, cirrhosis, depression and dementia. Alcohol use is also associated with suicide, homicide, domestic violence, sexually transmitted diseases and injuries. It is one of the leading behavior-related causes of death in New York City (NYC).
This site provides data on heavy alcohol consumption and alcohol outlets in NYC.
Alcohol and the EnvironmentGreater alcohol outlet density has been associated with a variety of health and social consequences, including:  Alcohol-related hospitalizations Violent crime, assault and homicide Child abuse and intimate partner violence Liver cirrhosis mortality Motor vehicle accidents  Alcohol advertising – at point-of-sale and other locations – permeates the NYC environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Data Sets</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/all-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/all-data/</guid>
      <description>Browse all data sets on the Environment and Health Data Portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bed Bugs</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</guid>
      <description>Bed bugs are small insects that feed mainly on human blood. They are often confused with other insects, and many people are not even aware of their presence until they have been bitten. However, not everyone has a reaction to bed bug bites. You may not discover that you have bed bugs until you see other signs of the pests such as, bed bugs themselves, their eggs or droppings, or the blood stains they leave behind in mattresses, box springs, chairs or other materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth Defects</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-defects/</guid>
      <description>Birth defects (also called congenital malformations) are conditions that happen when a baby does not develop normally during pregnancy. Structural defects may include missing limbs, malformed hearts, spina bifida and genetic conditions like Down syndrome. Most birth defects happen during the first three months of pregnancy and are detected within the first year of life. Some birth defects (such as cleft lip or clubfoot) are easy to see, but others (such as heart defects or hearing loss) are found using special tests (such as x-rays, CT scans, or hearing tests).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Close to 125,000 live births occur in New York City (NYC) each year. Most babies are born healthy, but those born prematurely or with low birth weight are at greater risk of disability or death. This site tracks indicators of fetal growth and development, infant and perinatal mortality, fertility and sex ratio at birth.
Birth Outcomes and the Environment Because many genetic and lifestyle factors influence growth and development of fetuses and babies, it can be difficult for researchers to study the effects of environmental exposures on birth outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancer/</guid>
      <description>Cancer is the general name for a group of more than 100 diseases in which cells in a part of the body begin to grow out of control. Cancers are named for the organ or type of cell in which they start.
Cancer occurs at all ages, but the risk increases with age. One of every two men, and one of every three women, will be diagnosed with cancer at some time in their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancers in Children</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</guid>
      <description>Cancer begins when cells in a part of the body start to grow out of control. There are many kinds of cancer, but they all start because of out-of-control growth of abnormal cells. Leukemia (cancer of the blood-forming cells) is the most common form of childhood cancer. There are different kinds of childhood leukemia. The most common kinds are acute lymphocytic leukemia (ALL) and acute myeloid leukemia (AML). Brain and other nervous system cancers are the second most common types of childhood cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Monoxide Incidents</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</guid>
      <description>Carbon monoxide (CO) is a poisonous gas that forms when fuel or other materials are burned. It is invisible and has no odor. Even short-term exposure to high levels of carbon monoxide can be fatal.
This site contains data on unintentional carbon monoxide incidents and emergency responses by the New York City Fire Department (FDNY), reports to the NYC Poison Control Center (PCC) of actual or potential carbon monoxide exposure and hospitalizations of NYC residents who have been poisoned by carbon monoxide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Monoxide Poisoning</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>Carbon monoxide (CO) is a poisonous gas that forms when fuel or other materials are burned. It is invisible and has no odor. Even short-term exposure to high levels of carbon monoxide can be fatal.
This site contains data on unintentional carbon monoxide incidents and emergency responses by the New York City Fire Department (FDNY), reports to the NYC Poison Control Center (PCC) of actual or potential carbon monoxide exposure and hospitalizations of NYC residents who have been poisoned by carbon monoxide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childhood Lead Exposure</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/childhood-lead-exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/childhood-lead-exposure/</guid>
      <description>Childhood lead poisoning is a serious but preventable public health problem. Lead is a toxic metal that can cause learning and behavior problems, and delay physical growth and mental development. Testing for lead poisoning is a key component of childhood lead poisoning prevention, since most children with elevated blood lead levels exhibit no symptoms.
This site provides data on blood lead testing and on elevated blood lead levels among NYC children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease/</guid>
      <description>More information coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cigarette Smoke</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cigarette-smoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cigarette-smoke/</guid>
      <description>Cigarette smoke contains over 250 toxic chemicals, more than 50 of which cause cancer. Secondhand smoke is a dangerous combination of the smoke from the burning of a cigarette, pipe, or cigar, and the smoke exhaled by a smoker. There is no safe level of secondhand smoke exposure. Even brief exposure can be harmful.
This site provides data on: teen and adult smoking, adults&#39; exposure to cigarette smoke at home or at work and adults with a policy banning smoking in their home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/climate/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events like heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes.
The world’s climate is shifting, becoming warmer with more precipitation and weather extremes. Over the past century in New York City, average temperatures have increased by 0.25°F per decade, precipitation by 0.72 inches per decade, and sea levels by 1.2 inches per decade. By the 2020s, a projected 25-30 days above 90°F are expected in a typical summer, resulting in more frequent and intense heat waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/climate-change/</guid>
      <description>There is broad consensus within the scientific community that human activity is changing the Earth&amp;rsquo;s climate through increasing concentrations of greenhouse gases (GHGs) — primarily carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), nitrous oxide (N2O), and chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) — in the atmosphere.
Scientists have predicted that unless GHG emissions are substantially stemmed by the end of the century, climate change will become irreversible.
A key part of combating climate change is mitigation, which means reducing GHG emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cockroaches</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cockroaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cockroaches/</guid>
      <description>Cockroaches, or just &amp;ldquo;roaches&amp;rdquo;, are a common urban pest. Though there are more than a thousand species of roaches, just a few are found in NYC homes. The most common are American Cockroaches, typically found in moist basements and lower floors, and German Cockroaches, found anywhere inside homes.
Cockroaches like warm, dark places such as toasters, clocks, microwave ovens, walls, and cabinets. They need regular access to food and water to live and breed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drinking Water Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/drinking-water-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/drinking-water-quality/</guid>
      <description>All NYC residences receive drinking water from a public water system. Most water is gravity fed from a network of reservoirs and lakes in protected watersheds, up to 125 miles from the city (view map).
The NYC water system consists of two surface water systems (Croton and Catskill/Delaware) and a Southwestern Queens ground water system. Since 1999, the Croton system has served as a supplemental water system, and the Catskill/Delaware reservoir system has supplied almost all NYC drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/energy/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Reduce energy consumption and make our energy systems cleaner and more reliable. To measure progress, we are tracking how our buildings are becoming more energy efficient as well as the extent to which our energy is becoming cleaner and more reliable.
Cleaner Energy To determine whether energy in NYC is getting cleaner, we track the carbon intensity of our electricity supply using a measure called an emissions coefficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falls Among Older Adults</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</guid>
      <description>Each year, one in three older adults (65 years and older) falls. Among New York City&amp;rsquo;s older adults, there are approximately 30,500 emergency department (ED) visits, 16,600 hospitalizations, and 300 deaths each year. Falls are not a normal part of aging, and research shows that many falls can be prevented.
Falls and the environment Although falls can occur anywhere, falls among older adults frequently happen at home. More than one-half of fall-related hospitalizations among older adults were due to falls in the home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Care</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-care/</guid>
      <description>More information coming soon. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Impacts of Air Pollution</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Attacks</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/heart-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/heart-attacks/</guid>
      <description>A heart attack is referred to medically as an acute myocardial infarction. It is caused when the blood flow that brings oxygen to the heart is severely reduced or cut off altogether. Without adequate blood flow, heart cells can quickly become injured or die. Most heart attacks are an acute event that follows years of atherosclerosis - a build up of plaque in the arteries around the heart. Factors in the environment may contribute to both atherosclerosis and to the acute event itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing/</guid>
      <description>No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.
In New York City, substandard or poor housing tends to cluster in neighborhoods. Homes that are deteriorating or dilapidated, or homes near buildings with broken or boarded-up windows, disproportionately tend to be in low-income neighborhoods, although the differences for these indicators have decreased.
Housing and Health Housing quality impacts health directly and indirectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Create homes for nearly a million more New Yorkers while making housing and neighborhoods more affordable and sustainable.
Housing Supply We are tracking the number of new housing units created since the start of the plan in 2007, as well as the size of the total housing stock, to ensure that the city is meeting the supply portion of its goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large City Air Quality Comparison</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/large-city-air-quality-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/large-city-air-quality-comparison/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Achieve the cleanest air quality of any big United States (US) city.
To measure progress towards this goal, we are tracking atmospheric concentrations of fine particulate matter (PM 2.5) in NYC compared to other large cities (populations greater than 1 million) in the US.
Air Quality and Sustainability Particulate matter is a complex mixture of very small solids and droplets suspended in air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lead Hazards</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/lead-hazards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/lead-hazards/</guid>
      <description>The main source of childhood lead poisoning in NYC, as in most of the United States, is lead-based paint in older, deteriorated housing. Nationwide, lead poisoning is associated with housing constructed before 1950, when lead-based paint was widely used and contained more lead than in later decades. In 1960, NYC banned the use of lead-based paint in homes and a national ban went into effect in 1978. Older layers of lead paint may still be present in older buildings and can become a lead hazard when the paint chips, peels or is abraded, or when renovations or repairs are conducted without taking appropriate actions to control dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mice and Rats</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</guid>
      <description>Rats and mice are common, but preventable. In NYC, rats tend to be seen on streets and sidewalks, and in backyards and basements, while mice are almost always found inside homes.
Rats and mice thrive where there are sources of food and shelter and where property owners fail to prevent and adequately respond to their presence.
This site provides survey data on the prevalence of mice or rats inside and outside of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/mortality/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noise</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/noise/</guid>
      <description>Ambient noise is sound from an environmental source, such as traffic, construction, industrial or recreation activities, animals, or people’s voices, that is unwanted to the person who hears it.
Noise and the Environment Exposure to any noise has long been recognized as an important occupational health hazard in workplaces and is increasingly viewed as a prevalent urban environmental hazard associated with adverse psychosocial and physiologic health effects such as sleep disturbance, higher blood pressure, cardiovascular disease, and impaired cognitive performance in children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overweight</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/overweight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/overweight/</guid>
      <description>People who are overweight or obese are at increased risk for heart disease and diabetes. Physical activity and healthy eating can promote well-being and relieve stress.
Weight and the Environment Neighborhood conditions and resources can encourage or discourage healthy behaviors. The density and types of food retail outlets available in neighborhoods may affect food shopping habits and nutrition choices of residents. Healthy food choices combined with physically active lifestyle support maintenance of an optimal bodyweight and overall good health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parks and Public Space</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/parks-and-public-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/parks-and-public-space/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Ensure that all New Yorkers live within a ten minute walk of a park.
Park Distance To be sure that nearly everyone is within a ten minute walk, we are tracking the numbers of New Yorkers who live within both a ½ and a ¼ mile of a park. These distances were chosen because people walk at different speeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesticides</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/pesticides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/pesticides/</guid>
      <description>Pesticides are chemicals applied to kill or control insects, rats and mice, undesirable plants and weeds, or fungi (e.g., mold). Pesticides are often categorized by type of use (e.g., rodenticide, insecticide) or chemical class (e.g., organophosphate, pyrethroid).
Modern pesticides have been developed to have less persistence in the environment than earlier chlorine-based chemicals such as DDT. Pesticides may be applied by a commercial applicator or a non-professional who has purchased a product from a store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Activity</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/physical-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/physical-activity/</guid>
      <description>Physical activity is an important part of a healthy lifestyle. Regular physical activity is associated with many health benefits, including improved fitness, prevention of weight gain, and lower risk of heart disease, stroke, high blood pressure, diabetes and some cancers. In addition, regular physical activity and healthy eating can promote well-being and relieve stress. For children, regular physical activity is also associated with improved academic performance.
Physical Activity and the Environment Neighborhood conditions and resources can encourage or discourage healthy behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant Food Safety</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/restaurant-food-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/restaurant-food-safety/</guid>
      <description>New York City has approximately 24,000 restaurants that the Health Department inspects every year to monitor compliance with city and state food safety regulations. At the end of an inspection, the Health Department gives restaurants a score, which is eventually converted to a grade of A, B or C. This site describes the distribution of A grades across New York City restaurants.
Restaurant Food Safety and Health Safe food handling can protect diners from foodborne illness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social and Economic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/social-and-economic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/social-and-economic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives. They are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.
People tend to be healthier when they have access to:
 Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities  But when people don’t have access to these conditions, they experience worse health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid Waste</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/solid-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/solid-waste/</guid>
      <description>PlaNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Divert 75% of solid waste from landfills.
Divert Solid Waste Of the city&amp;rsquo;s 13.6 million tons of waste per year, we currently recycle 51% of solid waste (including fill) and send 43% to landfills. The remainder is composted or converted to energy.
We are working to increase the amount diverted to recycling, composting, and conversion to 75%. Diverting solid waste from landfills to recycling and conversion facilities make use of our waste, creating new materials, nutrient sources, and energy out of our waste products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugary Drink Consumption</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/sugary-drink-consumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/sugary-drink-consumption/</guid>
      <description>Sugary drinks contribute to a higher-calorie diet, long-term weight gain, and increased risk of heart disease and diabetes. Sugary drinks provide little or no nutritional value, and because they don’t fill you up the way food does, you end up consuming more calories. Also, food and beverage portion sizes have exploded over the past several decades, and studies have shown that when given larger portions, people consume more without recognizing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/traffic/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Expand sustainable transportation choices and ensure the reliability and quality of our transportation network.
To measure progress towards this goal, we are tracking the switch to more sustainable modes of transportation (modal shift) and mass transit capacity, as well as whether our transportation system is meeting a state of good repair.
Modal Shift We are tracking the extent to which people are using non-automobile modes of transit including public transportation (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation-related Injuries</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Traffic injuries are no accident. Like other public health concerns, they are preventable through data driven solutions. In NYC, traffic injuries, which include injuries among pedestrians, bicyclists, motorcyclists, and motor vehicle occupants, are a leading cause of injury-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits.
In February 2014, NYC launched “Vision Zero”, an action plan to reduce injuries and deaths on city streets. Vision Zero is a multi-agency effort, incorporating road engineering, traffic enforcement, community outreach and education, and policy work to make NYC streets safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector-borne Disease</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</guid>
      <description>Vectorborne diseasesare diseases that are transmitted from an arthropod (usually a tick or mosquito, etc.) to humans or other animals. Some vectorborne disease agents are maintained primarily through transmission between arthropods and humans (e.g., dengue virus and malaria), while others are maintained between arthropods and animal reservoirs (e.g., Lyme disease and West Nile virus) and humans may become infected incidentally.
Vectorborne Disease and the Environment Climate is one of many important interacting variables that affect people’s risk for vectorborne diseases in New York City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/violence/</guid>
      <description>Violence is the use of physical, verbal, and/or emotional force to injure, harm, abuse, damage, or destroy. Interpersonal violence includes child abuse and neglect, youth violence, intimate partner violence, sexual violence, and elder abuse. Violence can involve injury to self, including self-harm, suicide attempts, and death by suicide. Violence can also take the form of power against a group or community.
Violence is a public health issue because it is a cause of morbidity and mortality, leading to physical and emotional harm, an increase in negative health outcomes, premature death, psychological trauma and persistent fear to individuals and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking, Driving, and Cycling</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/walking-driving-and-cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/walking-driving-and-cycling/</guid>
      <description>None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Supply</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/water-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/water-supply/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Ensure the high quality and reliability of our water supply system.
Drinking Water Quality If the NYC water network is properly maintained and operated, then we expect it to deliver consistently clean and potable water throughout the city. To ensure that our water supply is potable, the Department of Environmental Protection (DEP) collects approximately 15,000 drinking water samples and performs approximately 200,000 analyses of water quality annually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waterways</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/waterways/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/waterways/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Improve the quality of our waterways to increase opportunities for recreation and to restore coastal ecosystems.
New York State sets water quality standards, and NYC monitors New York Harbor water quality on an annual basis through the Harbor Survey. The survey uses 36 stations located throughout the open waters of the harbor and 19 stations located in smaller tributaries within the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather-Related Illness</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worker Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/worker-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/worker-health/</guid>
      <description>Every year in New York City, workers are injured on the job or become ill as a result of exposure to health hazards at work. However, most work-related illnesses and injuries are preventable – safer work environments can be achieved when workplace hazards are understood and appropriate prevention measures are put in place.
Data on work-related injuries and illness are used to show how often these preventable events occur and to identify factors that place workers at risk.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
