<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>heat on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/keywords/heat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in heat on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/keywords/heat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate and health</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/</guid>
      <description>Climate, including extreme weather, has a direct impact on health. As NYC&amp;rsquo;s climate changes, along with the world&amp;rsquo;s climate, we expect more frequent and intense heat waves, increased rainfall and more severe storms. These will add to existing weather-related risks. Already, heat kills more people than all other natural disasters combined.
In New York City, those most vulnerable to the dangers of hot weather are older adults and people with health conditions like heart disease, diabetes, and cognitive impairment - especially those in low-income, Black, and Brown communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/heat-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/heat-report/</guid>
      <description>Each summer, an estimated 370 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May - September.
Every year, the Health Department publishes a report on heat-related mortality. Click here to read the 2022 New York City Heat-Related Mortality Report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time heat-related illness</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/syndromic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 11:51:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/syndromic/</guid>
      <description>Extreme heat is dangerous. It can cause illness, make chronic conditions worse, and even kill. Heat-related illnesses happen when the body cannot cool down enough. These include:
Heat exhaustion Muscle cramps Fainting Heat stroke, the most serious form of heat-related illness Heat can also exacerbate chronic conditions, such as cardiovascular diseases or kidney conditions. These conditions may not be recognized or labeled as heat-related in a medical record but can be assessed using statistical models and are another a negative health outcome related to heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Heat Vulnerability Index</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/hvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:49:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/hvi/</guid>
      <description>Use this Heat Vulnerability Explorer to look up your the heat vulnerability of your neighborhood, and the neighborhood characteristics that affect it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The urban heat island effect in NYC</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-stories/localtemp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-stories/localtemp/</guid>
      <description>In New York City and across the country, more people die from extreme heat than from all other natural disasters combined. To understand how to keep New Yorkers safe from extreme heat, we studied neighborhood factors that affect temperature, and found that grass, shrubs, and trees can play a major role. Let’s take a look.
At 6.00 PM on June 30, 2018, the air temperature at the LaGuardia Airport Weather Station was 89° Fahrenheit (F).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather-related illness</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting New Yorkers from extreme heat</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-stories/heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-stories/heat/</guid>
      <description>Hot weather is dangerous. In New York City and across the country, more people on average die from extreme heat each year than from all other natural disasters.
Heat stress happens when your body’s temperature increases quickly. When the body can no longer control its temperature or cool itself down, it can lead to death.
At the NYC Health Department, we track heat stress deaths by reviewing causes of death recorded by the Bureau of Vital Statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What hot weather means for food safety</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-stories/food/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-stories/food/</guid>
      <description>New Yorkers eat out more than a billion times a year. To help keep diners safe, the Health Department educates restaurant operators about food safety practices and inspects all 27,000 city restaurants at least once a year. Over 90 percent of NYC restaurants have &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; grades in the window, showing excellent compliance with food safety requirements.
However, warmer weather creates special challenges keeping food safe. We dug into the data to find out how hot weather affects food safety.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
