<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bed bugs on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/bed-bugs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bed bugs on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/bed-bugs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/housing/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time at home - so the household environment can significantly affect health. Disrepair that stems from longterm maintenance neglect can lead to serious health problems, including: lead poisoning from lead paint; asthma and other respiratory issues triggered by pests; and carbon monoxide poisoning.
In NYC, substandard housing is disproportionately located in low-income neighborhoods, as historical disinvestment lead to severe, systemic maintenance deficiencies that threatens people&amp;rsquo;s health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bed Bugs</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</guid>
      <description>Bed bugs are small insects that feed mainly on human blood. They are often confused with other insects, and many people are not even aware of their presence until they have been bitten. However, not everyone has a reaction to bed bug bites. You may not discover that you have bed bugs until you see other signs of the pests such as, bed bugs themselves, their eggs or droppings, or the blood stains they leave behind in mattresses, box springs, chairs or other materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesticides</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/pesticides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/pesticides/</guid>
      <description>Pesticides are chemicals applied to kill or control insects, rats and mice, undesirable plants and weeds, or fungi (e.g., mold). Pesticides are often categorized by type of use (e.g., rodenticide, insecticide) or chemical class (e.g., organophosphate, pyrethroid).
Modern pesticides have been developed to have less persistence in the environment than earlier chlorine-based chemicals such as DDT. Pesticides may be applied by a commercial applicator or a non-professional who has purchased a product from a store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pests and Pesticides</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/pests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/pests/</guid>
      <description>Pests and pesticides can both have health effects. Household pests like mice, rats, and cockroaches can trigger asthma, while bed bugs are a well-known nuisance. Meanwhile, warmer winters may mean more vector-borne diseases like babesiosis and west nile virus.
Pesticides are chemicals used to control or kill insects, rats, mice, plants and weeds, or fungi (mold). Esposure to pesticides can occur from consuming foods or beverages that contain pesticide residues, from direct contact with the skin or eyes, or from breathing air in areas where pesticides are applied.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
