<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rodents on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/rodents/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rodents on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 11:14:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/rodents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rat Mitigation Zones</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/rat-mitigation-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/rat-mitigation-zones/</guid>
      <description>Rats can contaminate food, spread disease and reduce our quality of life. Rat Mitigation Zones (RMZ) are areas with high levels of rat activity, where City agencies focus resources to address rats and the conditions that support them.&#xA;Choose an RMZ on the map below to view data on complaints and NYC Health Department rat control activity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mice and rats</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</guid>
      <description>Rats and mice are common, but preventable. In NYC, rats tend to be seen on streets, alleys and sidewalks, and in yards and basements, while mice are almost always found inside buildings.&#xA;Rats and mice thrive where there are sources of food and shelter and where property owners fail to prevent and adequately respond to their presence.&#xA;Mice, Rats and Health Today, rats are recognized for their contribution to neighborhood stress, poor quality of life, contamination of food, potential threat to public health, and for their contribution to the destruction of infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pesticides</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/pesticides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/pesticides/</guid>
      <description>Pesticides are chemicals applied to kill or control insects, rats and mice, undesirable plants and weeds, or fungi (e.g., mold). Pesticides are often categorized by type of use (e.g., rodenticide, insecticide) or chemical class (e.g., organophosphate, pyrethroid).&#xA;Modern pesticides have been developed to have less persistence in the environment than earlier chlorine-based chemicals such as DDT. Pesticides may be applied by a commercial applicator or a non-professional who has purchased a product from a store.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
