<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>healthy housing on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/healthy-housing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in healthy housing on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/healthy-housing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asthma triggers at home</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma-triggers/</guid>
      <description>Housing conditions can trigger asthma. In New York City, childhood asthma is a significant health threat that affects thousands of children per year.&#xA;No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing maintenance</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>Buildings with maintenance issues and disrepair can harm health. Across NYC, low-income neighborhoods have a higher percentage of buildings in disrepair due to past and present disinvestment and housing discrimination. This housing disrepair harms residents&amp;rsquo; health.&#xA;No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury. All building owners are required by law to provide essential services such as heat and hot water, make timely repairs, and maintain a pest-free building.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing safety</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-safety/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health - both in terms of safety characteristics within the home, and in terms of factors that affect housing stability.&#xA;Safety characteristics A home&amp;rsquo;s safety characteristics might include:&#xA;Air conditioning, which is a vital tool to protect people who are at risk of heat-related illness and death Electric medical equipment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing stability</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-stability/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health.&#xA;Housing stability In NYC, about one out of every three homes is owned by the person living there - about half the national average. Owning a home is a powerful way to build intergenerational wealth, but historical and contemporary disinvestment and housing discrimination has made it hard for many New Yorkers to own homes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
