<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storms on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/storms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storms on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 09:01:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/storms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Hurricane Ida and Superstorm Sandy taught us about flooding and health</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/flooding-and-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 09:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/flooding-and-health/</guid>
      <description>Superstorm Sandy (2012) and rainfall from Hurricane Ida (2021) broke records in NYC and resulted in injury and death. Both showed how the climate crisis is affecting the strength of storms and how profound the threat of flooding is to New Yorkers’ health.&#xA;Superstorm Sandy’s coastal flooding damaged hundreds of thousands of homes When Superstorm Sandy hit New York City in October 2012, 52 people died as a result of injuries and there were increases in deaths from other causes, such as chronic health conditions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate and health</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/climatehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/climatehealth/</guid>
      <description>Climate, including extreme weather, has a direct impact on health. As NYC&amp;rsquo;s climate changes, along with the world&amp;rsquo;s climate, we expect more frequent and intense heat waves, increased rainfall and more severe storms. These will add to existing weather-related risks. Already, heat kills more people than all other natural disasters combined.&#xA;In New York City, those most vulnerable to the dangers of hot weather are older adults and people with health conditions like heart disease, diabetes, and cognitive impairment - especially those in low-income, Black, and Brown communities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/climate/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events like heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes.&#xA;The world’s climate is shifting, becoming warmer with more precipitation and weather extremes. Over the past century in New York City, average temperatures have increased by 0.25°F per decade, precipitation by 0.72 inches per decade, and sea levels by 1.2 inches per decade. By the 2020s, a projected 25-30 days above 90°F are expected in a typical summer, resulting in more frequent and intense heat waves.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
