<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>housing on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/keywords/housing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in housing on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 01:18:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/keywords/housing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Housing creates health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/housing-creates-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 01:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/housing-creates-health/</guid>
      <description>Health is determined by many factors, and people tend to be healthier when they have economic stability, live in quality housing and have access to public space and safe, connected communities. In 2020, the NYC Health Department held a series of community conversations with residents and local stakeholders across 26 neighborhoods. New Yorkers shared personal stories that illuminate their priorities for building healthier neighborhoods, healthier childhoods and more. This is one part of a three-part series on how housing, economic stability and public space create health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A walk through history</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/block-by-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 08:49:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/block-by-block/</guid>
      <description>A neighborhood is not only shaped by its residents, but also by governmental practices and policies. Some of these have discriminated against residents because of the color of their skin and have segregated neighborhoods across the nation - including in New York City. This timeline is a selection of key processes and policies that shaped the physical environment and population of East Harlem, and some of the efforts to respond to local issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying safe in cold weather</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 13:11:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/cold/</guid>
      <description>Cold weather can be dangerous. Here are some tips for staying safe this winter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Displacement Risk</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/displacement-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/displacement-risk/</guid>
      <description>Housing stability creates health, but in NYC, many people have difficulty accessing healthy, stable housing.&#xA;In some neighborhoods, residents at are higher risk of being displaced - forced to leave their homes, and their neighborhoods, due combinations of market pressure, rent burden, housing conditions, poverty, and injustice in the housing market.&#xA;To show people&amp;rsquo;s risk of being forced out of their homes or neighborhoods, the Department of City Planning and the Department of Housing Preservation and Development created a Displacement Risk Index, part of the Equitable Development Data Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/key-topics/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/key-topics/housing/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time at home - so the household environment can significantly affect health. Disrepair that stems from long-term maintenance neglect can lead to serious health problems, including: lead poisoning from lead paint; asthma and other respiratory issues triggered by pests; and carbon monoxide poisoning.&#xA;In NYC, substandard housing is disproportionately located in low-income neighborhoods, as historical disinvestment lead to severe, systemic maintenance deficiencies that threatens people&amp;rsquo;s health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The urban heat island effect in NYC</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/urban-heat-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/urban-heat-island/</guid>
      <description>In New York City and across the country, more people die from extreme heat than from all other natural disasters combined. To understand how to keep New Yorkers safe from extreme heat, we studied neighborhood factors that affect temperature, and found that grass, shrubs, and trees can play a major role. Let’s take a look.&#xA;At 6.00 PM on June 30, 2018, the air temperature at the LaGuardia Airport Weather Station was 89° Fahrenheit (F).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.&#xA;Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma triggers at home</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/asthma-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/asthma-triggers/</guid>
      <description>Housing conditions can trigger asthma. In New York City, childhood asthma is a significant health threat that affects thousands of children per year.&#xA;No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bed bugs</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</guid>
      <description>Bed bugs are small insects that feed mainly on human blood. They are often confused with other insects, and many people are not even aware of their presence until they have been bitten. However, not everyone has a reaction to bed bug bites. You may not discover that you have bed bugs until you see other signs of the pests such as, bed bugs themselves, their eggs or droppings, or the blood stains they leave behind in mattresses, box springs, chairs or other materials.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</guid>
      <description>Carbon monoxide (CO) is a poisonous gas that forms when fuel or other materials are burned. It is invisible and has no odor. Even short-term exposure to high levels of carbon monoxide can be fatal. Carbon monoxide blocks oxygen transport in the body. Symptoms of mild carbon monoxide poisoning include headache, nausea, fatigue, dizziness and disorientation. Breathing high concentrations of carbon monoxide can cause somebody to lose consciousness and have permanent neurological injury - or even death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cockroaches</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/cockroaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/cockroaches/</guid>
      <description>Cockroaches are a common urban pest. Though there are more than a thousand species of roaches, just a few are found in NYC homes. The most common are American Cockroaches, typically found in moist basements and lower floors, and German Cockroaches, found anywhere inside homes.&#xA;Cockroaches like warm, dark places such as toasters, clocks, microwave ovens, walls, and cabinets. They need regular access to food and water to live and breed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drinking water quality</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/drinking-water-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/drinking-water-quality/</guid>
      <description>All NYC residences receive drinking water from a public water system. Most water is gravity fed from a network of reservoirs and lakes in protected watersheds, up to 125 miles from the city.&#xA;The NYC water system consists of two surface water systems: Croton and Catskill/Delaware and one groundwater system, in Southwestern Queens. Since 1999, the Croton system has served as a supplemental water system. The Catskill/Delaware reservoir system supplies almost all NYC drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic conditions</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities Access to these are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Falls among older adults</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</guid>
      <description>Each year, one in three older adults (65 years and older) falls. Among New York City&amp;rsquo;s older adults, there are approximately 30,500 emergency department (ED) visits, 16,600 hospitalizations, and 300 deaths each year. Falls are not a normal part of aging, and research shows that many falls can be prevented.&#xA;Falls and the environment Although falls can occur anywhere, falls among older adults frequently happen at home. More than one-half of fall-related hospitalizations among older adults were due to falls in the home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing maintenance</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/housing-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/housing-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>Buildings with maintenance issues and disrepair can harm health. Across NYC, low-income neighborhoods have a higher percentage of buildings in disrepair due to past and present disinvestment and housing discrimination. This housing disrepair harms residents&amp;rsquo; health.&#xA;No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury. All building owners are required by law to provide essential services such as heat and hot water, make timely repairs, and maintain a pest-free building.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing safety</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/housing-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/housing-safety/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health - both in terms of safety characteristics within the home, and in terms of factors that affect housing stability.&#xA;Safety characteristics A home&amp;rsquo;s safety characteristics might include:&#xA;Air conditioning, which is a vital tool to protect people who are at risk of heat-related illness and death Electric medical equipment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing stability</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/housing-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/housing-stability/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health.&#xA;Housing stability In NYC, about one out of every three homes is owned by the person living there - about half the national average. Owning a home is a powerful way to build intergenerational wealth, but historical and contemporary disinvestment and housing discrimination has made it hard for many New Yorkers to own homes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead poisoning</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/lead/</guid>
      <description>Lead is a metal that is toxic to people. There is no safe level of lead in your body. It can cause learning and behavior problems, and delay physical growth and mental development.&#xA;In the past, it was used in gasoline, paint, ceramics, caulking, pipes and solder. In 1960, NYC banned the use of lead-based paint in homes. A national ban came into effect in 1978. Leaded gasoline was phased out beginning in the 1970&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mice and rats</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</guid>
      <description>Rats and mice are common, but preventable. In NYC, rats tend to be seen on streets and sidewalks, and in backyards and basements, while mice are almost always found inside homes.&#xA;Rats and mice thrive where there are sources of food and shelter and where property owners fail to prevent and adequately respond to their presence.&#xA;This site provides survey data on the prevalence of mice or rats inside and outside of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social conditions</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/social-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/social-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities But when people don’t have access to these conditions, they experience worse health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/key-topics/childhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/key-topics/childhealth/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong health can be determined by your health when you are a child. Plus, children can be fragile, and can be more harmed by environmental threats. So, ways that the environment can affect health often are particularly important for child health.&#xA;In New York City, several environmental factors play a key role in determining childhood health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of redlining</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/redlining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/redlining/</guid>
      <description>Inside the 90-year-old financial policy that harms our health In public health, we often cite structural racism to help explain health patterns in our society. But what, specifically, does this mean? A close look at the history of redlining shows this connection.&#xA;When we analyze data on the health of New Yorkers, we often find the same geographic patterns, with higher rates of preventable health conditions in high-poverty neighborhoods. For example, we&amp;rsquo;ve written about how asthma and poverty are closely connected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health, housing, and history</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/housing/</guid>
      <description>For health, place matters What determines whether or not you’re healthy? You may think about what you eat, whether you exercise, whether you smoke and your family medical history.&#xA;But you may not think about how your home affects your health - and you may not think about the factors that influence where you live. For a home to be healthy, it should be free of: Cracks Holes Leaks Smoke Pests Old, peeling paint In other words, a healthy home is a well-maintained home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why asthma is a social justice issue</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/asthma-and-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/asthma-and-poverty/</guid>
      <description>Poverty affects health in many ways. In New York City, the story of asthma clearly illustrates this connection.&#xA;To understand the connection between poverty and asthma, take a look at this map of poverty rates in New York City, below. The darker the color, the more residents living in poverty.&#xA;Now, compare that to a map of emergency department visits for asthma in children age 5 to 17, below. The darker the color, the higher the rate of children visiting the emergency department with asthma.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
