<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>environmental health on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/environmental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in environmental health on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/environmental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cancer</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancer/</guid>
      <description>Cancer is the general name for a group of more than 100 diseases in which cells in a part of the body begin to grow out of control. Cancers are named for the organ or type of cell in which they start.
Cancer occurs at all ages, but the risk increases with age. One of every two men, and one of every three women, will be diagnosed with cancer at some time in their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancers in Children</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</guid>
      <description>Cancer begins when cells in a part of the body start to grow out of control. There are many kinds of cancer, but they all start because of out-of-control growth of abnormal cells. Leukemia (cancer of the blood-forming cells) is the most common form of childhood cancer. There are different kinds of childhood leukemia. The most common kinds are acute lymphocytic leukemia (ALL) and acute myeloid leukemia (AML). Brain and other nervous system cancers are the second most common types of childhood cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food and Drink</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/foodanddrink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:58:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/foodanddrink/</guid>
      <description>We all make choices around food and drink, but sometimes, those choices are made for us by our food environments.
Our food environments include neighborhood-level alcohol access, unhealthy food access, and restaurant food safety. Additionally, drinking water quality data includes data on contaminants that are most frequently found at levels that may be of public health significant in the country&amp;rsquo;s drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
