<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hospitalizations on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/hospitalizations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hospitalizations on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/hospitalizations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falls Among Older Adults</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</guid>
      <description>Each year, one in three older adults (65 years and older) falls. Among New York City&amp;rsquo;s older adults, there are approximately 30,500 emergency department (ED) visits, 16,600 hospitalizations, and 300 deaths each year. Falls are not a normal part of aging, and research shows that many falls can be prevented.
Falls and the environment Although falls can occur anywhere, falls among older adults frequently happen at home. More than one-half of fall-related hospitalizations among older adults were due to falls in the home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Impacts of Air Pollution</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Attacks</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/heart-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/heart-attacks/</guid>
      <description>A heart attack is referred to medically as an acute myocardial infarction. It is caused when the blood flow that brings oxygen to the heart is severely reduced or cut off altogether. Without adequate blood flow, heart cells can quickly become injured or die. Most heart attacks are an acute event that follows years of atherosclerosis - a build up of plaque in the arteries around the heart. Factors in the environment may contribute to both atherosclerosis and to the acute event itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large City Air Quality Comparison</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/large-city-air-quality-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/large-city-air-quality-comparison/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Achieve the cleanest air quality of any big United States (US) city.
To measure progress towards this goal, we are tracking atmospheric concentrations of fine particulate matter (PM 2.5) in NYC compared to other large cities (populations greater than 1 million) in the US.
Air Quality and Sustainability Particulate matter is a complex mixture of very small solids and droplets suspended in air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Expand sustainable transportation choices and ensure the reliability and quality of our transportation network.
To measure progress towards this goal, we are tracking the switch to more sustainable modes of transportation (modal shift) and mass transit capacity, as well as whether our transportation system is meeting a state of good repair.
Modal Shift We are tracking the extent to which people are using non-automobile modes of transit including public transportation (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation-related Injuries</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Traffic injuries are no accident. Like other public health concerns, they are preventable through data driven solutions. In NYC, traffic injuries, which include injuries among pedestrians, bicyclists, motorcyclists, and motor vehicle occupants, are a leading cause of injury-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits.
In February 2014, NYC launched “Vision Zero”, an action plan to reduce injuries and deaths on city streets. Vision Zero is a multi-agency effort, incorporating road engineering, traffic enforcement, community outreach and education, and policy work to make NYC streets safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather-Related Illness</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environments matter: the road to street safety in NYC</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 10:54:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 public health emergency has changed New York City in many ways -including how we get around the city. Asthe city continues to adapt to COVID-19, New Yorkers will look for ways to getaround that feel safe - redistributing transit among different modes to easecrowding and increase safety on public transportation.As more New Yorkers use bicycles, let&#39;s take a look at safety on our streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disparities in violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/assaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 08:29:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/assaults/</guid>
      <description>Violence has profound effects. An assault, a shooting, a homicide, or any use of force affects people in many deep ways.
Violence causes physical and emotional harm. It can inflict fear, a constant sense of unease. It can cause short- and long-term trauma. Violence can affect people throughout their lives - including their health. It can lead to poor birth outcomes, compromised childhood development, negative health behaviors, physical and mental illness, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
