<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>foodanddrink on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/foodanddrink/</link>
    <description>Recent content in foodanddrink on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 08:33:22 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/foodanddrink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An update on air quality during COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aqcovid2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aqcovid2/</guid>
      <description>Big improvements in outdoor air quality during COVID-19 reveal impacts of traffic and commercial cooking On March 20, 2020, New York State announced the COVID-19 shutdown, officially known as NY Pause. In NYC, it lasted until June 8, 2020.
With stay-at-home orders in NY and other states, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air quality changed significantly. Earlier, we looked at data collected from real-time air pollution monitors to see how day-to-day pollution changed when people started to stay home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol Access</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-access/</guid>
      <description>Heavy regular drinking and binge drinking contribute to a wide range of chronic health problems, including heart disease, diabetes, cancer, stroke, cirrhosis, depression and dementia. Alcohol use is also associated with suicide, homicide, domestic violence, sexually transmitted diseases and injuries. It is one of the leading behavior-related causes of death in New York City (NYC).
This site provides data on heavy alcohol consumption and alcohol outlets in NYC.
Alcohol and the Environment Greater alcohol outlet density has been associated with a variety of health and social consequences, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol Use</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-use/</guid>
      <description>Heavy regular drinking and binge drinking contribute to a wide range of chronic health problems, including heart disease, diabetes, cancer, stroke, cirrhosis, depression and dementia. Alcohol use is also associated with suicide, homicide, domestic violence, sexually transmitted diseases and injuries. It is one of the leading behavior-related causes of death in New York City (NYC).
This site provides data on heavy alcohol consumption and alcohol outlets in NYC.
Alcohol and the EnvironmentGreater alcohol outlet density has been associated with a variety of health and social consequences, including:  Alcohol-related hospitalizations Violent crime, assault and homicide Child abuse and intimate partner violence Liver cirrhosis mortality Motor vehicle accidents  Alcohol advertising – at point-of-sale and other locations – permeates the NYC environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drinking Water Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/drinking-water-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/drinking-water-quality/</guid>
      <description>All NYC residences receive drinking water from a public water system. Most water is gravity fed from a network of reservoirs and lakes in protected watersheds, up to 125 miles from the city (view map).
The NYC water system consists of two surface water systems (Croton and Catskill/Delaware) and a Southwestern Queens ground water system. Since 1999, the Croton system has served as a supplemental water system, and the Catskill/Delaware reservoir system has supplied almost all NYC drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant Food Safety</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/restaurant-food-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/restaurant-food-safety/</guid>
      <description>New York City has approximately 24,000 restaurants that the Health Department inspects every year to monitor compliance with city and state food safety regulations. At the end of an inspection, the Health Department gives restaurants a score, which is eventually converted to a grade of A, B or C. This site describes the distribution of A grades across New York City restaurants.
Restaurant Food Safety and Health Safe food handling can protect diners from foodborne illness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugary Drink Consumption</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/sugary-drink-consumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/sugary-drink-consumption/</guid>
      <description>Sugary drinks contribute to a higher-calorie diet, long-term weight gain, and increased risk of heart disease and diabetes. Sugary drinks provide little or no nutritional value, and because they don’t fill you up the way food does, you end up consuming more calories. Also, food and beverage portion sizes have exploded over the past several decades, and studies have shown that when given larger portions, people consume more without recognizing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Supply</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/water-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/water-supply/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Ensure the high quality and reliability of our water supply system.
Drinking Water Quality If the NYC water network is properly maintained and operated, then we expect it to deliver consistently clean and potable water throughout the city. To ensure that our water supply is potable, the Department of Environmental Protection (DEP) collects approximately 15,000 drinking water samples and performs approximately 200,000 analyses of water quality annually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food and Drink</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/foodanddrink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:58:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/foodanddrink/</guid>
      <description>We all make choices around food and drink, but sometimes, those choices are made for us by our food environments.
Our food environments include neighborhood-level alcohol access, unhealthy food access, and restaurant food safety. Additionally, drinking water quality data includes data on contaminants that are most frequently found at levels that may be of public health significant in the country&amp;rsquo;s drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking changes in New York City&#39;s sources of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aq-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 12:02:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aq-cooking/</guid>
      <description>As city life changes, so does its air quality, as sources of emissions that affect the city&amp;rsquo;s outdoor air quality, like truck traffic, building boilers and restaurants, also change. For more than a decade, we have been tracking air quality through the NYC Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) and exploring the factors that drive neighborhood differences. We have found some interesting changes in the sources of air pollution across NYC neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What hot weather means for food safety</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/food/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/food/</guid>
      <description>New Yorkers eat out more than a billion times a year. To help keep diners safe, the Health Department educates restaurant operators about food safety practices and inspects all 27,000 city restaurants at least once a year. Over 90 percent of NYC restaurants have &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; grades in the window, showing excellent compliance with food safety requirements.
However, warmer weather creates special challenges keeping food safe. We dug into the data to find out how hot weather affects food safety.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
