<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lungs on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/lungs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lungs on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:23:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/lungs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Efforts to reduce air pollution should focus on neighborhoods with the worst health impacts.</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/hia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:23:23 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/hia/</guid>
      <description>Every year in NYC between 2015 and 2017 (the most recent years for which this analysis is available), fine particulate matter pollution from motor vehicles and burning fossil fuels caused:&#xA;At least 2,000 deaths About 1,400 hospital admissions for lung and heart conditions 3,750 emergency department admissions for asthma Since air pollution causes significant illness and death in New York City, it&amp;rsquo;s important to reduce air pollution. So where do we start?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZAPPA: A tool to understand air quality policies</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/zappa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/zappa/</guid>
      <description>How do we know what air quality policies will have the biggest effect? New York City’s air quality is generally good and has been improving over time. Still, air pollution threatens health: two pollutants, ozone and PM2.5 cause about 2,400 deaths per year in NYC, and thousands more emergency department visits and hospitalizations for asthma, heart, and lung problems.&#xA;It’s important to clean up the air to protect New Yorkers, and we know how to do it: reduce emissions from buildings, vehicles, restaurants, power plants, and other sources of pollutants.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An update on air quality during COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aqcovid2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aqcovid2/</guid>
      <description>Big improvements in outdoor air quality during COVID-19 reveal impacts of traffic and commercial cooking On March 20, 2020, New York State announced the COVID-19 shutdown, officially known as NY Pause. In NYC, it lasted until June 8, 2020.&#xA;With stay-at-home orders in NY and other states, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air quality changed significantly. Earlier, we looked at data collected from real-time air pollution monitors to see how day-to-day pollution changed when people started to stay home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/airquality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 12:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/airquality/</guid>
      <description>New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, drops of liquid, gasses, and other pollution that can affect health. Bad air quality can be particularly dangerous for older adults, children, and people with heart or lung conditions.&#xA;Air quality varies from neighborhood to neighborhood, based on local levels of emissions and many other factors. We monitor air quality using the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS), NYC&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive air quality monitoring and modeling network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.&#xA;Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter and ground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.&#xA;Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health impacts of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking changes in New York City&#39;s sources of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aq-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 12:02:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aq-cooking/</guid>
      <description>As city life changes, so does its air quality, as sources of emissions that affect the city&amp;rsquo;s outdoor air quality, like truck traffic, building boilers and restaurants, also change. For more than a decade, we have been tracking air quality through the NYC Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) and exploring the factors that drive neighborhood differences. We have found some interesting changes in the sources of air pollution across NYC neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality during COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aqcovid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aqcovid/</guid>
      <description>What happens when NYC stays home? The COVID-19 pandemic upended the lives of all New Yorkers. The outbreak has affected many aspects of our daily life, but there are also less apparent effects, such as impacts on our environment.&#xA;The NYC Community Air Survey uses air quality monitors to take hourly measurements of fine particulate (PM2.5) at a few sites around the city.&#xA;Generally, locations around the city see changes in PM2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality snapshots: special findings from 10 years of NYCCAS</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aqsnapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:37:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aqsnapshots/</guid>
      <description>Skip Nav A traffic health threat: air toxics Noise levels that harm health The benefits of cleaner fuel Special monitoring for environmental justice For 10 years, the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) has measured air quality at 100 locations around NYC. We’ve combined these measurements with data on things related to air quality - like traffic, building emissions, green space, and much more - to model seasonal air quality in every New York City neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality in car-free areas</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aqts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aqts/</guid>
      <description>Does the air improve in car-free zones? People often ask us this, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great question. To answer, we turn to the NYC Community Air Survey, or NYCCAS. NYCCAS is our network of air quality monitors around the city.&#xA;NYCCAS monitors air with nearly 100 sensors across the city We use these monitors to measure levels of six different pollutants: fine particles (PM2.5), nitrogen dioxide (NO2), nitric oxide (NO), sulfur dioxide (SO2), ozone (O3), and black carbon (BC).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What our air quality monitors tell us about NYC&#39;s neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aq2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/aq2/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, we looked at data from the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) - a network of about 100 air quality monitors - to see if air quality improves in areas that go car-free. And the answer is yes.&#xA;NYCCAS tells us that more traffic means more air pollution nearby. So, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t have a nearby monitor, we can predict that an area that goes car-free (like Park Drive in Prospect Park, for example) sees an improvement in air quality.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
