<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 12:32:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Environmental health outcomes</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/healthoutcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 12:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/healthoutcomes/</guid>
      <description>Our environment - the world around us - affects our health. Here are datasets on health outcomes that people experience that may be linked to the environment.&#xA;Some of these have clear links to the environment, like lead poisoning. Others have some uncertain links, and are still being investigated and understood.&#xA;But while specific health outcomes may have stronger or weaker links to the environment, the environment&amp;rsquo;s overall effect on our health is clear - we know that one of the strongest predictors of health is where you&amp;rsquo;re born.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active design</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/active-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/active-design/</guid>
      <description>Physical activity and healthy eating are among the leading ways to get and stay healthy.&#xA;Active design is an applied, evidence-informed approach to improve physical, mental and social health outcomes through the design of the built environment.&#xA;To improve health, we can:&#xA;Increase access to public parks and recreation Create pedestrian plazas, and maintain sidewalks Plant street trees Provide safer cycling infrastructure and secure bicycle storage Make stairways attractive and accessible Strategies like these can have a measurable effect on people’s ability to safely maintain their physical, mental, and social health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/climate/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events like heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes.&#xA;The world’s climate is shifting, becoming warmer with more precipitation and weather extremes. Over the past century in New York City, average temperatures have increased by 0.25°F per decade, precipitation by 0.72 inches per decade, and sea levels by 1.2 inches per decade. By the 2020s, a projected 25-30 days above 90°F are expected in a typical summer, resulting in more frequent and intense heat waves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic conditions</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities Access to these are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mortality</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mortality/</guid>
      <description>Death is, of course, a severe health outcome. Many deaths are preventable.&#xA;Premature mortality lets us look at deaths before age 65. It can be a useful way to indicate the overall health of the population.&#xA;Neonatal deaths, postneonatal deaths, and infant deaths let us look at deaths among the the youngest members of our communities. Infants, with new, developing bodies, can be very susceptible to environmental threats - like poisonings, accidents, and injuries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical activity</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/physical-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/physical-activity/</guid>
      <description>Physical activity is an important part of a healthy lifestyle. Regular physical activity is associated with many health benefits, including improved fitness, prevention of weight gain, and lower risk of heart disease, stroke, high blood pressure, diabetes and some cancers. In addition, regular physical activity and healthy eating can promote well-being and relieve stress. For children, regular physical activity is also associated with improved academic performance.&#xA;Physical Activity and the Environment Neighborhood conditions and resources can encourage or discourage healthy behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social conditions</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/social-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/social-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities But when people don’t have access to these conditions, they experience worse health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
