<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>transportation on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/transportation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in transportation on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 07:58:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/transportation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transportation and Active Design</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 07:58:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/transportation/</guid>
      <description>Physical inactivity and unhealthy diet rank among the leading risk factors for premature death in the United States. Active design, however, promotes health by using architectural and urban design strategies to encourage walking, bicycling, stair climbing, transit use, active recreation, and healthy eating.
Designing to increase access to parks, create pedestrian plazas, ensure well-maintained sidewalks, plant street trees, provide secure bicycle storage, and make stairwaus in buildings attractive and accessible can have a measurable effect on people&amp;rsquo;s ability to safetly get regular physical activity that can keep them healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Design</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/active-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/active-design/</guid>
      <description>Physical inactivity and unhealthy diet rank among the leading risk factors for premature death in the United States. Active design promotes health by using architectural and urban design strategies to encourage stair climbing, walking, bicycling, transit use, active recreation and healthy eating.
What we can do:
 Increase access to public parks and recreation. Create pedestrian plazas. Ensure well-maintained sidewalks. Plant street trees. Provide secure bicycle storage. Make stairways in buildings attractive and accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.
Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter andground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.
Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Impacts of Air Pollution</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large City Air Quality Comparison</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/large-city-air-quality-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/large-city-air-quality-comparison/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Achieve the cleanest air quality of any big United States (US) city.
To measure progress towards this goal, we are tracking atmospheric concentrations of fine particulate matter (PM 2.5) in NYC compared to other large cities (populations greater than 1 million) in the US.
Air Quality and Sustainability Particulate matter is a complex mixture of very small solids and droplets suspended in air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noise</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/noise/</guid>
      <description>Ambient noise is sound from an environmental source, such as traffic, construction, industrial or recreation activities, animals, or people’s voices, that is unwanted to the person who hears it.
Noise and the Environment Exposure to any noise has long been recognized as an important occupational health hazard in workplaces and is increasingly viewed as a prevalent urban environmental hazard associated with adverse psychosocial and physiologic health effects such as sleep disturbance, higher blood pressure, cardiovascular disease, and impaired cognitive performance in children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parks and Public Space</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/parks-and-public-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/parks-and-public-space/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Ensure that all New Yorkers live within a ten minute walk of a park.
Park Distance To be sure that nearly everyone is within a ten minute walk, we are tracking the numbers of New Yorkers who live within both a ½ and a ¼ mile of a park. These distances were chosen because people walk at different speeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Activity</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/physical-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/physical-activity/</guid>
      <description>Physical activity is an important part of a healthy lifestyle. Regular physical activity is associated with many health benefits, including improved fitness, prevention of weight gain, and lower risk of heart disease, stroke, high blood pressure, diabetes and some cancers. In addition, regular physical activity and healthy eating can promote well-being and relieve stress. For children, regular physical activity is also associated with improved academic performance.
Physical Activity and the Environment Neighborhood conditions and resources can encourage or discourage healthy behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/traffic/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Expand sustainable transportation choices and ensure the reliability and quality of our transportation network.
To measure progress towards this goal, we are tracking the switch to more sustainable modes of transportation (modal shift) and mass transit capacity, as well as whether our transportation system is meeting a state of good repair.
Modal Shift We are tracking the extent to which people are using non-automobile modes of transit including public transportation (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation-related Injuries</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Traffic injuries are no accident. Like other public health concerns, they are preventable through data driven solutions. In NYC, traffic injuries, which include injuries among pedestrians, bicyclists, motorcyclists, and motor vehicle occupants, are a leading cause of injury-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits.
In February 2014, NYC launched “Vision Zero”, an action plan to reduce injuries and deaths on city streets. Vision Zero is a multi-agency effort, incorporating road engineering, traffic enforcement, community outreach and education, and policy work to make NYC streets safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking, Driving, and Cycling</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/walking-driving-and-cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/walking-driving-and-cycling/</guid>
      <description>None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waterways</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/waterways/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/waterways/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Improve the quality of our waterways to increase opportunities for recreation and to restore coastal ecosystems.
New York State sets water quality standards, and NYC monitors New York Harbor water quality on an annual basis through the Harbor Survey. The survey uses 36 stations located throughout the open waters of the harbor and 19 stations located in smaller tributaries within the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environments matter: the road to street safety in NYC</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 10:54:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 public health emergency has changed New York City in many ways -including how we get around the city. Asthe city continues to adapt to COVID-19, New Yorkers will look for ways to getaround that feel safe - redistributing transit among different modes to easecrowding and increase safety on public transportation.As more New Yorkers use bicycles, let&#39;s take a look at safety on our streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air quality during COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aqcovid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aqcovid/</guid>
      <description>What happens when NYC stays home? The COVID-19 pandemic upended the lives of all New Yorkers. The outbreak has affected many aspects of our daily life, but there are also less apparent effects, such as impacts on our environment.
The NYC Community Air Survey uses air quality monitors to take hourly measurements of fine particulate (PM2.5) at a few sites around the city.
Generally, locations around the city see changes in PM2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air quality snapshots: special findings from 10 years of NYCCAS</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aqsnapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:37:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aqsnapshots/</guid>
      <description>Skip NavAir quality snapshots: 10 years of NYC air quality monitoringA traffic health threat: air toxicsNoise levels that harm healthThe benefits of cleaner fuelSpecial monitoring for environmental justiceFor 10 years, the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) has measured air quality at 100 locations around NYC. We’ve combined these measurements with data on things related to air quality - like traffic, building emissions, green space, and much more - to model seasonal air quality in every New York City neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air quality in car-free areas</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aqts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aqts/</guid>
      <description>Does the air improve in car-free zones? People often ask us this, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great question. To answer, we turn to the NYC Community Air Survey, or NYCCAS. NYCCAS is our network of air quality monitors around the city.
NYCCAS monitors air with nearly 100 sensors across the city NYCCAS air quality monitor sites: Routinesite, environmental justicesite, retired site.We use these monitors to measure levels of six different pollutants: fine particles (PM2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What our air quality monitors tell us about NYC&#39;s neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aq2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/aq2/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, we looked at data from the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) - a network of about 100 air quality monitors - to see if air quality improves in areas that go car-free. And the answer is yes.
NYCCAS tells us that more traffic means more air pollution nearby. So, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t have a nearby monitor, we can predict that an area that goes car-free (like Park Drive in Prospect Park, for example) sees an improvement in air quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Design, Physical Activity and Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood-reports/activedesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood-reports/activedesign/</guid>
      <description>The design and conditions of buildings, streets, public transportation and parks influence physical activity, use of active transportation and other healthy behavior. A neighborhood&amp;rsquo;s features can also impact the safety of its residents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma and the Environment</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood-reports/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood-reports/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common lung disease and a leading cause of hospitalizations for children under 15 years old. This report provides a summary of asthma indicators by neighborhood. It also describes housing and neighborhood characteristics that can make asthma worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Air and Health in NYC</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood-reports/outdoorair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood-reports/outdoorair/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is one of the most important environmental threats to urban populations and while all people are exposed, pollutant emissions, levels of exposure, and population vulnerability vary across neighborhoods. Exposures to common air pollutants have been linked to respiratory and cardiovascular diseases, cancers, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
