<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 08:29:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disparities in violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/assaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 08:29:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/assaults/</guid>
      <description>Violence has profound effects An assault, a shooting, a homicide, or any use of force affects people in many deep ways.
Violence causes physical and emotional harm. It can inflict fear, a constant sense of unease. It can cause short- and long-term trauma. Violence can affect people throughout their lives - including their health. It can lead to poor birth outcomes, compromised childhood development, negative health behaviors, physical and mental illness, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social and Economic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/social/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives. They are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.
People tend to be healthier when they have access to economic and financial stability, higher education, adequate health care, healthy neighborhoods, and safe, strong communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/asthma_mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:38:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/asthma_mm/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why asthma is a social justice issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/povasthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 12:44:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/povasthma/</guid>
      <description>Poverty can affect how you breathe Poverty affects health in many ways. In New York City, the story of asthma clearly illustrates this connection.
To understand the connection between poverty and asthma, take a look at this map of poverty rates in New York City, below. The darker the color, the more residents living in poverty.
!function(){&#34;use strict&#34;;window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;])for(var t in a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;]){var e=document.getElementById(&#34;datawrapper-chart-&#34;+t);e&amp;&amp;(e.style.height=a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;][t]+&#34;px&#34;)}})}(); Now, compare that to a map of emergency department visits for asthma in children age 5 to 17, below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
