<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:49:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Heat Vulnerability Index</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/climatehealth/hvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:49:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/climatehealth/hvi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childhood Lead Exposure</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/childhood-lead-exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/childhood-lead-exposure/</guid>
      <description>Childhood Lead Exposure About Childhood Lead Exposure Childhood lead poisoning is a serious but preventable public health problem. Lead is a toxic metal that can cause learning and behavior problems, and delay physical growth and mental development. Testing for lead poisoning is a key component of childhood lead poisoning prevention, since most children with elevated blood lead levels exhibit no symptoms.
This site provides data on blood lead testing and on elevated blood lead levels among NYC children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disparity</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/disparity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/disparity/</guid>
      <description>Disparity Neighborhood Poverty</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Care</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/health-care/</guid>
      <description>Health Care More information coming soon. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/housing/</guid>
      <description>Housing About Housing Quality No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.
In New York City, substandard or poor housing tends to cluster in neighborhoods. Homes that are deteriorating or dilapidated, or homes near buildings with broken or boarded-up windows, disproportionately tend to be in low-income neighborhoods, although the differences for these indicators have decreased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>Housing and Neighborhoods Housing and Neighborhoods OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Create homes for nearly a million more New Yorkers while making housing and neighborhoods more affordable and sustainable.
Housing Supply We are tracking the number of new housing units created since the start of the plan in 2007, as well as the size of the total housing stock, to ensure that the city is meeting the supply portion of its goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lead Hazards</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/lead-hazards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/lead-hazards/</guid>
      <description>Lead Hazards About Lead Hazards The main source of childhood lead poisoning in NYC, as in most of the United States, is lead-based paint in older, deteriorated housing. Nationwide, lead poisoning is associated with housing constructed before 1950, when lead-based paint was widely used and contained more lead than in later decades. In 1960, NYC banned the use of lead-based paint in homes and a national ban went into effect in 1978.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/population-characteristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/population-characteristics/</guid>
      <description>Population Characteristics Coming Soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race and Ethnicity</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/race-and-ethnicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/race-and-ethnicity/</guid>
      <description>Race and Ethnicity None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social and Economic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/social-and-economic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/social-and-economic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and Economic Conditions Social and economic conditions Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives. They are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.
People tend to be healthier when they have access to:
 Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities   But when people don’t have access to these conditions, they experience worse health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/violence/</guid>
      <description>Violence About Violence in New York City Violence is the use of physical, verbal, and/or emotional force to injure, harm, abuse, damage, or destroy. Interpersonal violence includes child abuse and neglect, youth violence, intimate partner violence, sexual violence, and elder abuse. Violence can involve injury to self, including self-harm, suicide attempts, and death by suicide. Violence can also take the form of power against a group or community.
Violence is a public health issue because it is a cause of morbidity and mortality, leading to physical and emotional harm, an increase in negative health outcomes, premature death, psychological trauma and persistent fear to individuals and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Vulnerability More information coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather-Related Illness</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>Weather-Related Illness About Climate, Weather, and Health A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worker Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/worker-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/worker-health/</guid>
      <description>Worker Health About Worker Health and Safety Every year in New York City, workers are injured on the job or become ill as a result of exposure to health hazards at work. However, most work-related illnesses and injuries are preventable – safer work environments can be achieved when workplace hazards are understood and appropriate prevention measures are put in place.
Data on work-related injuries and illness are used to show how often these preventable events occur and to identify factors that place workers at risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social and Economic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/social/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives. They are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.
People tend to be healthier when they have access to economic and financial stability, higher education, adequate health care, healthy neighborhoods, and safe, strong communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/asthma_mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:38:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/asthma_mm/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why violence is a public health issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/violence/</guid>
      <description>Using public health to prevent violence    Experiencing violence affects people in many ways. It not only causes physical injury or death, but being exposed to it can also cause emotional and psychological trauma. Violence doesn’t just affect the immediate victim, it affects their surrounding community, too. Violence can affect people throughout their lives: it is associated with worse birth outcomes, childhood developmental delays, physical and mental illness, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of redlining</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/redlining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/redlining/</guid>
      <description>Inside the 90-year-old financial policy that harms our health  In public health, we often cite structural racism to help explain health patterns in our society. But what, specifically, does this mean? A close look at the history of redlining shows this connection.
When we analyze data on the health of New Yorkers, we often find the same geographic patterns, with higher rates of preventable health conditions in high-poverty neighborhoods. For example, we&amp;rsquo;ve written about how asthma and poverty are closely connected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health, housing, and history</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/housing/</guid>
      <description>For health, place matters.  What determines whether or not you’re healthy? You may think about what you eat, whether you exercise, whether you smoke and your family medical history.
But you may not think about how your home affects your health - and you may not think about the factors that influence where you live. For a home to be healthy, it should be free of:  Cracks Holes Leaks Smoke Pests Old, peeling paint  In other words, a healthy home is a well-maintained home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting New Yorkers from extreme heat</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/heat/</guid>
      <description>Hot weather is dangerous. In New York City and across the country, more people on average die from extreme heat each year than from all other natural disasters.
Heat stress happens when your body’s temperature increases quickly. When the body can no longer control its temperature or cool itself down, it can lead to death.
At the NYC Health Department, we track heat stress deaths by reviewing causes of death recorded by the Bureau of Vital Statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disparities in violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/assaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 08:29:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/assaults/</guid>
      <description>Violence has profound effects. An assault, a shooting, a homicide, or any use of force affects people in many deep ways.
Violence causes physical and emotional harm. It can inflict fear, a constant sense of unease. It can cause short- and long-term trauma. Violence can affect people throughout their lives - including their health. It can lead to poor birth outcomes, compromised childhood development, negative health behaviors, physical and mental illness, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why asthma is a social justice issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/povasthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/povasthma/</guid>
      <description>Poverty affects health in many ways. In New York City, the story of asthma clearly illustrates this connection.
To understand the connection between poverty and asthma, take a look at this map of poverty rates in New York City, below. The darker the color, the more residents living in poverty.
  !function () { &#34;use strict&#34;; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function (a) { if (void 0 !== a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;]) for (var e in a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma and the Environment</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood_reports/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood_reports/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma and the Environment Neighborhood Report Landing Page.
Asthma is a common lung disease and a leading cause of hospitalizations for children under 15 years old. This report provides a summary of asthma indicators by neighborhood. It also describes housing and neighborhood characteristics that can make asthma worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate and Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood_reports/climateandhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood_reports/climateandhealth/</guid>
      <description>Climate and Health Neighborhood Report Landing Page.
Extreme heat, coastal storms, flooding and episodes of elevated ozone are climate-related hazards that may increase with climate change and have important public health impacts in New York City. Extreme weather can cause power outages, which also threaten public health. This report provides neighborhood indicators of climate-related hazards, vulnerability and health impacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood_reports/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/neighborhood_reports/housing/</guid>
      <description>Housing and Health Neighborhood Report Landing Page.
This report provides a neighborhood summary of housing conditions and related health outcomes. It also describes population characteristics that can increase vulnerability to housing hazards.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
