<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pollution on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/keywords/pollution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pollution on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/keywords/pollution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waterways</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/waterways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/waterways/</guid>
      <description>Healthy waterways are important for both aquatic life and humans who use the water for recreation.&#xA;We measure the quality of harbor water through two key indicators:&#xA;Dissolved oxygen is essential for most aquatic life. Coastal habitats and ecosystems thrive in environments with high concentrations of dissolved oxygen.&#xA;Concentrations of fecal coliform bacteria and Enterococci bacteria. Higher levels of these bacteria can mean there is sewage-related water pollution. Though most of these bacteria do not cause disease, higher concentrations can indicate the presence of pathogenic (disease-producing) bacteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efforts to reduce air pollution should focus on neighborhoods with the worst health impacts</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/hia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:23:23 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/hia/</guid>
      <description>Every year in NYC between 2015 and 2017 (the most recent years for which this analysis is available), fine particulate matter pollution from motor vehicles and burning fossil fuels caused:&#xA;At least 2,000 deaths About 1,400 hospital admissions for lung and heart conditions 3,750 emergency department admissions for asthma Since air pollution causes significant illness and death in New York City, it&amp;rsquo;s important to reduce air pollution. So where do we start?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/key-topics/airquality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 12:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/key-topics/airquality/</guid>
      <description>New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, drops of liquid, gasses, and other pollution that can affect health. Bad air quality can be particularly dangerous for older adults, children, and people with heart or lung conditions.&#xA;Air quality varies from neighborhood to neighborhood, based on local levels of emissions and many other factors. We monitor air quality using the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS), NYC&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive air quality monitoring and modeling network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.&#xA;Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter and ground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.&#xA;Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health impacts of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking changes in New York City&#39;s sources of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/restaurants-and-air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 12:02:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/restaurants-and-air-quality/</guid>
      <description>As city life changes, so does its air quality, as sources of emissions that affect the city&amp;rsquo;s outdoor air quality, like truck traffic, building boilers and restaurants, also change. For more than a decade, we have been tracking air quality through the NYC Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) and exploring the factors that drive neighborhood differences. We have found some interesting changes in the sources of air pollution across NYC neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality in car-free areas</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/car-free-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/car-free-zones/</guid>
      <description>Does the air improve in car-free zones? People often ask us this, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great question. To answer, we turn to the NYC Community Air Survey, or NYCCAS. NYCCAS is our network of air quality monitors around the city.&#xA;NYCCAS monitors air with nearly 100 sensors across the city We use these monitors to measure levels of six different pollutants: fine particles (PM2.5), nitrogen dioxide (NO2), nitric oxide (NO), sulfur dioxide (SO2), ozone (O3), and black carbon (BC).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What our air quality monitors tell us about NYC&#39;s neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/air-quality-by-neighborhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/air-quality-by-neighborhood/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, we looked at data from the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) - a network of about 100 air quality monitors - to see if air quality improves in areas that go car-free. And the answer is yes.&#xA;NYCCAS tells us that more traffic means more air pollution nearby. So, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t have a nearby monitor, we can predict that an area that goes car-free (like Park Drive in Prospect Park, for example) sees an improvement in air quality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breathe easy: NYC&#39;s air quality is improving</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/breatheeasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/breatheeasy/</guid>
      <description>The air we breathe can have a major effect on our health — air pollution can make asthma worse and can cause heart disease, lung disease, strokes, and even cancer.&#xA;Fortunately, New York City has made great strides in recent years to improve air quality. Let’s take a look.&#xA;An air quality advisory day happens when air pollution builds up to dangerous levels. It means that people who are sensitive to air pollution (like people with respiratory or heart problems) should spend less time outside and avoid outdoor exercise.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
