<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>children on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/children/</link>
    <description>Recent content in children on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/children/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth Defects</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-defects/</guid>
      <description>Birth defects (also called congenital malformations) are conditions that happen when a baby does not develop normally during pregnancy. Structural defects may include missing limbs, malformed hearts, spina bifida and genetic conditions like Down syndrome. Most birth defects happen during the first three months of pregnancy and are detected within the first year of life. Some birth defects (such as cleft lip or clubfoot) are easy to see, but others (such as heart defects or hearing loss) are found using special tests (such as x-rays, CT scans, or hearing tests).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Close to 125,000 live births occur in New York City (NYC) each year. Most babies are born healthy, but those born prematurely or with low birth weight are at greater risk of disability or death. This site tracks indicators of fetal growth and development, infant and perinatal mortality, fertility and sex ratio at birth.
Birth Outcomes and the Environment Because many genetic and lifestyle factors influence growth and development of fetuses and babies, it can be difficult for researchers to study the effects of environmental exposures on birth outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancer/</guid>
      <description>Cancer is the general name for a group of more than 100 diseases in which cells in a part of the body begin to grow out of control. Cancers are named for the organ or type of cell in which they start.
Cancer occurs at all ages, but the risk increases with age. One of every two men, and one of every three women, will be diagnosed with cancer at some time in their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancers in Children</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</guid>
      <description>Cancer begins when cells in a part of the body start to grow out of control. There are many kinds of cancer, but they all start because of out-of-control growth of abnormal cells. Leukemia (cancer of the blood-forming cells) is the most common form of childhood cancer. There are different kinds of childhood leukemia. The most common kinds are acute lymphocytic leukemia (ALL) and acute myeloid leukemia (AML). Brain and other nervous system cancers are the second most common types of childhood cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Monoxide Incidents</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</guid>
      <description>Carbon monoxide (CO) is a poisonous gas that forms when fuel or other materials are burned. It is invisible and has no odor. Even short-term exposure to high levels of carbon monoxide can be fatal.
This site contains data on unintentional carbon monoxide incidents and emergency responses by the New York City Fire Department (FDNY), reports to the NYC Poison Control Center (PCC) of actual or potential carbon monoxide exposure and hospitalizations of NYC residents who have been poisoned by carbon monoxide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Monoxide Poisoning</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>Carbon monoxide (CO) is a poisonous gas that forms when fuel or other materials are burned. It is invisible and has no odor. Even short-term exposure to high levels of carbon monoxide can be fatal.
This site contains data on unintentional carbon monoxide incidents and emergency responses by the New York City Fire Department (FDNY), reports to the NYC Poison Control Center (PCC) of actual or potential carbon monoxide exposure and hospitalizations of NYC residents who have been poisoned by carbon monoxide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childhood Lead Exposure</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/childhood-lead-exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/childhood-lead-exposure/</guid>
      <description>Childhood lead poisoning is a serious but preventable public health problem. Lead is a toxic metal that can cause learning and behavior problems, and delay physical growth and mental development. Testing for lead poisoning is a key component of childhood lead poisoning prevention, since most children with elevated blood lead levels exhibit no symptoms.
This site provides data on blood lead testing and on elevated blood lead levels among NYC children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cigarette Smoke</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cigarette-smoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cigarette-smoke/</guid>
      <description>Cigarette smoke contains over 250 toxic chemicals, more than 50 of which cause cancer. Secondhand smoke is a dangerous combination of the smoke from the burning of a cigarette, pipe, or cigar, and the smoke exhaled by a smoker. There is no safe level of secondhand smoke exposure. Even brief exposure can be harmful.
This site provides data on: teen and adult smoking, adults&#39; exposure to cigarette smoke at home or at work and adults with a policy banning smoking in their home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lead Hazards</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/lead-hazards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/lead-hazards/</guid>
      <description>The main source of childhood lead poisoning in NYC, as in most of the United States, is lead-based paint in older, deteriorated housing. Nationwide, lead poisoning is associated with housing constructed before 1950, when lead-based paint was widely used and contained more lead than in later decades. In 1960, NYC banned the use of lead-based paint in homes and a national ban went into effect in 1978. Older layers of lead paint may still be present in older buildings and can become a lead hazard when the paint chips, peels or is abraded, or when renovations or repairs are conducted without taking appropriate actions to control dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/childhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/childhealth/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong health can be determined by your health when you are a child. Plus, children can be fragile, and can be more harmed by environmental threats. So, ways that the environment can affect health often are particularly important for child health.
In New York City, several environmental factors play a key role in determining childhood health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why asthma is a social justice issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/povasthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/povasthma/</guid>
      <description>Poverty affects health in many ways. In New York City, the story of asthma clearly illustrates this connection.
To understand the connection between poverty and asthma, take a look at this map of poverty rates in New York City, below. The darker the color, the more residents living in poverty.
!function () { &#34;use strict&#34;; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function (a) { if (void 0 !== a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;]) for (var e in a.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
