<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>active design on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/active-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in active design on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:59:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/active-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:59:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>Our neighborhoods are the world around us. The built environment and the social environment where we spend most of our time affect health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Design</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/active-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/active-design/</guid>
      <description>Physical inactivity and unhealthy diet rank among the leading risk factors for premature death in the United States. Active design promotes health by using architectural and urban design strategies to encourage stair climbing, walking, bicycling, transit use, active recreation and healthy eating.
What we can do:
 Increase access to public parks and recreation. Create pedestrian plazas. Ensure well-maintained sidewalks. Plant street trees. Provide secure bicycle storage. Make stairways in buildings attractive and accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Create homes for nearly a million more New Yorkers while making housing and neighborhoods more affordable and sustainable.
Housing Supply We are tracking the number of new housing units created since the start of the plan in 2007, as well as the size of the total housing stock, to ensure that the city is meeting the supply portion of its goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Activity</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/physical-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/physical-activity/</guid>
      <description>Physical activity is an important part of a healthy lifestyle. Regular physical activity is associated with many health benefits, including improved fitness, prevention of weight gain, and lower risk of heart disease, stroke, high blood pressure, diabetes and some cancers. In addition, regular physical activity and healthy eating can promote well-being and relieve stress. For children, regular physical activity is also associated with improved academic performance.
Physical Activity and the Environment Neighborhood conditions and resources can encourage or discourage healthy behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environments matter: the road to street safety in NYC</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 10:54:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 public health emergency has changed New York City in many ways - including how we get around the city. As the city continues to adapt to COVID-19, New Yorkers will look for ways to get around that feel safe - redistributing transit among different modes to ease crowding and increase safety on public transportation. As more New Yorkers use bicycles, let&#39;s take a look at safety on our streets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
