<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About the EH Data Portal on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About the EH Data Portal on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 13:30:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The redesigned EH Data Portal</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/about/redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 08:49:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/about/redesign/</guid>
      <description>The Environment and Health Data Portal looks a little bit different! We recently redesigned our site to make it easier for you to find important data and information on how the environment affects health. Here&amp;rsquo;s what the new site has to offer: An updated design:&#xA;The whole site got a fresh design to make exploring easier for you – whether you’re on a desktop computer, a phone, or a tablet. It&amp;rsquo;s been optimized for accessibility, translation, and clear, simple presentation of information, using the NYC Core Framework, an open-source framework based on Bootstrap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Hiring!</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/about/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 13:30:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/about/jobs/</guid>
      <description>Join our team! See below for open positions in our bureau - or, search cityjobs.nyc.gov for &amp;lsquo;BESP&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;Senior Evaluator: We are hiring an experienced evaluator who will develop and implement of an evaluation strategy for the agency&amp;rsquo;s community climate resiliency program portfolio, and oversee and implement analytic plans for program evaluation projects.&#xA;Director of Data Management: We&amp;rsquo;re hiring somebody to work with the Division of Information Technology (DIT) to create and manage data integration processes, oversee and manage analytic databases and attendant governance policies, create views and stored procedures, and manage the reporting server.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
