<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>climatehealth on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/categories/climatehealth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in climatehealth on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:10:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/categories/climatehealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waterways</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/waterways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/waterways/</guid>
      <description>Healthy waterways are important for both aquatic life and humans who use the water for recreation.&#xA;We measure the quality of harbor water through two key indicators:&#xA;Dissolved oxygen is essential for most aquatic life. Coastal habitats and ecosystems thrive in environments with high concentrations of dissolved oxygen.&#xA;Concentrations of fecal coliform bacteria and Enterococci bacteria. Higher levels of these bacteria can mean there is sewage-related water pollution. Though most of these bacteria do not cause disease, higher concentrations can indicate the presence of pathogenic (disease-producing) bacteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying safe in cold weather</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 13:11:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/cold/</guid>
      <description>Cold weather can be dangerous. Here are some tips for staying safe this winter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How power outages affect health</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/poweroutages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:34:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/poweroutages/</guid>
      <description>Imagine your child has asthma. One summer night, a powerful storm rolls in and knocks the power out.&#xA;Your child starts to have trouble breathing. Usually, you’d use a home nebulizer, an electric machine that turns liquid medicine into a mist that your child breathes in through a face mask.&#xA;But the power is out. Without the nebulizer, your child’s breathing gets worse - and you wonder, is it time to go to the hospital again?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate and health</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/climatehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/climatehealth/</guid>
      <description>Climate, including extreme weather, has a direct impact on health. As NYC&amp;rsquo;s climate changes, along with the world&amp;rsquo;s climate, we expect more frequent and intense heat waves, increased rainfall and more severe storms. These will add to existing weather-related risks. Already, heat kills more people than all other natural disasters combined.&#xA;In New York City, those most vulnerable to the dangers of hot weather are older adults and people with health conditions like heart disease, diabetes, and cognitive impairment - especially those in low-income, Black, and Brown communities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-report-archive/2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-report-archive/2021/</guid>
      <description>Summary: Heat Stress Deaths Each summer from 2010-2019, there were, on average,10 heat stress deaths (those caused directly by heat) in New York City (NYC). Lack of home air conditioning (AC) continues to be an important risk factor for heat stress death. Among those who died from heat stress, the place of death was most often an un-air-conditioned home. Black New Yorkers are more likely to die from heat stress, with death rates two times higher than among other New Yorkers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-report-archive/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-report-archive/2022/</guid>
      <description>Summary Each summer, an estimated 370 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May - September. Of the 370 deaths:&#xA;From 2011-2020, there was an average of 10 heat-stress deaths (caused directly by heat). From 2011-2019, there was an average of about 360 heat-exacerbated deaths (caused indirectly by heat aggravating an underlying illness).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-report-archive/2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-report-archive/2023/</guid>
      <description>Summary Each summer, on average, an estimated 350 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May through September. Of the 350 deaths: From 2012-2021, there were an average of 7 heat-stress deaths (caused directly by heat). From 2016-2020, there were an average of about 345 heat-exacerbated deaths (caused indirectly by heat aggravating an underlying illness).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-report/</guid>
      <description>Each summer, on average, an estimated 350 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May through September.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-time heat-related illness</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 11:51:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/heat-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>The weather forecast is the best way to predict heat-related health outcomes.&#xA;We can also track heat-related illness with near real-time electronic data from emergency departments at hospitals throughout NYC. These data include illnesses directly attributed to heat (including heat exhaustion, muscle cramps, fainting and heat stroke), not the full burden of heat-related health impacts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Heat Vulnerability Index</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/hvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:49:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-features/hvi/</guid>
      <description>Use this Heat Vulnerability Explorer to look up your the heat vulnerability of your neighborhood, and the neighborhood characteristics that affect it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The urban heat island effect in NYC</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/urban-heat-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/urban-heat-island/</guid>
      <description>In New York City and across the country, more people die from extreme heat than from all other natural disasters combined. To understand how to keep New Yorkers safe from extreme heat, we studied neighborhood factors that affect temperature, and found that grass, shrubs, and trees can play a major role. Let’s take a look.&#xA;At 6.00 PM on June 30, 2018, the air temperature at the LaGuardia Airport Weather Station was 89° Fahrenheit (F).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.&#xA;Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/climate/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events like heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes.&#xA;The world’s climate is shifting, becoming warmer with more precipitation and weather extremes. Over the past century in New York City, average temperatures have increased by 0.25°F per decade, precipitation by 0.72 inches per decade, and sea levels by 1.2 inches per decade. By the 2020s, a projected 25-30 days above 90°F are expected in a typical summer, resulting in more frequent and intense heat waves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing safety</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-safety/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health - both in terms of safety characteristics within the home, and in terms of factors that affect housing stability.&#xA;Safety characteristics A home&amp;rsquo;s safety characteristics might include:&#xA;Air conditioning, which is a vital tool to protect people who are at risk of heat-related illness and death Electric medical equipment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing stability</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-stability/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health.&#xA;Housing stability In NYC, about one out of every three homes is owned by the person living there - about half the national average. Owning a home is a powerful way to build intergenerational wealth, but historical and contemporary disinvestment and housing discrimination has made it hard for many New Yorkers to own homes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vector-borne disease</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</guid>
      <description>Vectorborne diseases are diseases that are transmitted from an arthropod (usually a tick or mosquito, etc.) to humans or other animals. Some vectorborne disease agents are maintained primarily through transmission between arthropods and humans (e.g., dengue virus and malaria), while others are maintained between arthropods and animal reservoirs (e.g., Lyme disease and West Nile virus) and humans may become infected incidentally.&#xA;Vectorborne Disease and the Environment Climate is one of many important interacting variables that affect people’s risk for vectorborne diseases in New York City.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weather-related illness</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting New Yorkers from extreme heat</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/heat/</guid>
      <description>Hot weather is dangerous. In New York City and across the country, more people on average die from extreme heat each year than from all other natural disasters.&#xA;Heat stress happens when your body’s temperature increases quickly. When the body can no longer control its temperature or cool itself down, it can lead to death.&#xA;At the NYC Health Department, we track heat stress deaths by reviewing causes of death recorded by the Bureau of Vital Statistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What hot weather means for food safety</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/food/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/food/</guid>
      <description>New Yorkers eat out more than a billion times a year. To help keep diners safe, the Health Department educates restaurant operators about food safety practices and inspects all 27,000 city restaurants at least once a year. Over 90 percent of NYC restaurants have &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; grades in the window, showing excellent compliance with food safety requirements.&#xA;However, warmer weather creates special challenges keeping food safe. We dug into the data to find out how hot weather affects food safety.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate and Health</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/neighborhood-reports/climate_and_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/neighborhood-reports/climate_and_health/</guid>
      <description>Extreme heat, coastal storms, and flooding are climate-related hazards that are increasing because of climate change. They have important public health impacts in New York City. Extreme weather can cause power outages, which also threaten public health. This report provides neighborhood indicators of climate-related hazards, populations that may be most affected, built environment factors that can increase risk, and health impacts.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
