<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Explorer on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Explorer on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 09:34:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waterways</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/waterways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/waterways/</guid>
      <description>Healthy waterways are important for both aquatic life and humans who use the water for recreation.&#xA;We measure the quality of harbor water through two key indicators:&#xA;Dissolved oxygen is essential for most aquatic life. Coastal habitats and ecosystems thrive in environments with high concentrations of dissolved oxygen.&#xA;Concentrations of fecal coliform bacteria and Enterococci bacteria. Higher levels of these bacteria can mean there is sewage-related water pollution. Though most of these bacteria do not cause disease, higher concentrations can indicate the presence of pathogenic (disease-producing) bacteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthy eating</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/healthy-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 12:01:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/healthy-eating/</guid>
      <description>Healthy eating is associated with better health, including a reduced risk of cardiovascular disease. That means that having access to healthy, safe, and affordable food choices is crucial for a person to achieve healthy eating habits.&#xA;Food access is influenced by many environmental factors, including proximity to food retail outlets and neighborhood-level resources (like neighborhood poverty, and availability of public transportation).&#xA;Sugary drinks contribute to a higher-calorie diet, increased risk of heart disease and diabetes, and long-term weight gain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active design</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/active-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/active-design/</guid>
      <description>Physical activity and healthy eating are among the leading ways to get and stay healthy.&#xA;Active design is an applied, evidence-informed approach to improve physical, mental and social health outcomes through the design of the built environment.&#xA;To improve health, we can:&#xA;Increase access to public parks and recreation Create pedestrian plazas, and maintain sidewalks Plant street trees Provide safer cycling infrastructure and secure bicycle storage Make stairways attractive and accessible Strategies like these can have a measurable effect on people’s ability to safely maintain their physical, mental, and social health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.&#xA;Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter and ground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.&#xA;Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol access and use</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/alcohol-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/alcohol-use/</guid>
      <description>Heavy regular drinking and binge drinking contribute to a wide range of chronic health problems, including heart disease, diabetes, cancer, stroke, cirrhosis, depression and dementia. Alcohol use is also associated with suicide, homicide, domestic violence, sexually transmitted diseases and injuries. It is one of the leading behavior-related causes of death in New York City (NYC).&#xA;This site provides data on heavy alcohol consumption and alcohol outlets in NYC.&#xA;Alcohol and the Environment Greater alcohol outlet density has been associated with a variety of health and social consequences, including:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.&#xA;Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma triggers at home</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/asthma-triggers/</guid>
      <description>Housing conditions can trigger asthma. In New York City, childhood asthma is a significant health threat that affects thousands of children per year.&#xA;No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bed bugs</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/bed-bugs/</guid>
      <description>Bed bugs are small insects that feed mainly on human blood. They are often confused with other insects, and many people are not even aware of their presence until they have been bitten. However, not everyone has a reaction to bed bug bites. You may not discover that you have bed bugs until you see other signs of the pests such as, bed bugs themselves, their eggs or droppings, or the blood stains they leave behind in mattresses, box springs, chairs or other materials.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birth defects</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/birth-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/birth-defects/</guid>
      <description>Birth defects (also called congenital malformations) are conditions that happen when a baby does not develop normally during pregnancy. Structural defects may include missing limbs, malformed hearts, spina bifida and genetic conditions like Down Syndrome. Most birth defects happen during the first three months of pregnancy and are detected within the first year of life. Some birth defects (such as cleft lip or clubfoot) are easy to see, but others (such as heart defects or hearing loss) are found using special tests (such as x-rays, CT scans, or hearing tests).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birth outcomes</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Close to 125,000 live births occur in New York City (NYC) each year. Most babies are born healthy, but those born prematurely or with low birth weight are at greater risk of disability or death. This site tracks indicators of fetal growth and development, infant and perinatal mortality, fertility and sex ratio at birth.&#xA;Birth Outcomes and the Environment Because many genetic and lifestyle factors influence growth and development of fetuses and babies, it can be difficult for researchers to study the effects of environmental exposures on birth outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cancer</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cancer/</guid>
      <description>Cancer is the general name for a group of more than 100 diseases in which cells in a part of the body begin to grow out of control.&#xA;In New York City cancer kills nearly 13,000 residents every year, with smoking as the leading cause. One of every two men, and one of every three women, will be diagnosed with cancer at some time in their life. In women, breast is the most common type of cancer diagnosed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cancers in children</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</guid>
      <description>Cancer begins when cells in a part of the body start to grow out of control. There are many kinds of cancer, but they all start because of out-of-control growth of abnormal cells. Leukemia (cancer of the blood-forming cells) is the most common form of childhood cancer. There are different kinds of childhood leukemia. The most common kinds are acute lymphocytic leukemia and acute myeloid leukemia . Brain and other nervous system cancers are the second most common types of childhood cancers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</guid>
      <description>Carbon monoxide (CO) is a poisonous gas that forms when fuel or other materials are burned. It is invisible and has no odor.&#xA;Even short-term exposure to high levels of carbon monoxide can be fatal. Carbon monoxide blocks oxygen transport in the body. Symptoms of mild carbon monoxide poisoning include headache, nausea, fatigue, dizziness and disorientation. Breathing high concentrations of carbon monoxide can cause somebody to lose consciousness and have permanent neurological injury - or even death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cigarette smoke</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cigarette-smoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cigarette-smoke/</guid>
      <description>Smoking causes over a dozen cancers, heart disease, stroke, type 2 diabetes and many other diseases; it remains a leading cause of death in New York City (NYC). On average, people who do not smoke live about 10 years longer than people who do.&#xA;Additionally, there is no safe level of exposure to secondhand smoke. Secondhand smoke causes cancer, heart disease and other illnesses in adults. Children exposed to smoke are more likely to have bronchitis, asthma attacks, ear infections, pneumonia and sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/climate/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events like heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes.&#xA;The world’s climate is shifting, becoming warmer with more precipitation and weather extremes. Over the past century in New York City, average temperatures have increased by 0.25°F per decade, precipitation by 0.72 inches per decade, and sea levels by 1.2 inches per decade. By the 2020s, a projected 25-30 days above 90°F are expected in a typical summer, resulting in more frequent and intense heat waves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cockroaches</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cockroaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/cockroaches/</guid>
      <description>Cockroaches are a common urban pest. Though there are more than a thousand species of roaches, just a few are found in NYC homes. The most common are American Cockroaches, typically found in moist basements and lower floors, and German Cockroaches, found anywhere inside homes.&#xA;Cockroaches like warm, dark places such as toasters, clocks, microwave ovens, walls, and cabinets. They need regular access to food and water to live and breed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data index</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/data-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/data-index/</guid>
      <description>Search by term, see available years and geographies, and filter by data source.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drinking water quality</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/drinking-water-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/drinking-water-quality/</guid>
      <description>All NYC residences receive drinking water from a public water system. Most water is gravity fed from a network of reservoirs and lakes in protected watersheds, up to 125 miles from the city.&#xA;The NYC water system consists of two surface water systems: Croton and Catskill/Delaware and one groundwater system, in Southwestern Queens. Since 1999, the Croton system has served as a supplemental water system. The Catskill/Delaware reservoir system supplies almost all NYC drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic conditions</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities Access to these are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Falls among older adults</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</guid>
      <description>Each year, one in three older adults (65 years and older) falls. Among New York City&amp;rsquo;s older adults, there are approximately 30,500 emergency department (ED) visits, 16,600 hospitalizations, and 300 deaths each year. Falls are not a normal part of aging, and research shows that many falls can be prevented.&#xA;Falls and the environment Although falls can occur anywhere, falls among older adults frequently happen at home. More than one-half of fall-related hospitalizations among older adults were due to falls in the home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health care</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/health-care/</guid>
      <description>Health care is a valuable tool to stay healthy.&#xA;Health insurance coverage is associated with many health benefits. People with health insurance are more likely to have a regular doctor, receive preventive care services, better manage chronic health conditions, have longer life expectancy, and more.&#xA;However, not all New Yorkers can access appropriate amounts of care. Many New Yorkers remain uninsured. People without access to appropriate health care don&amp;rsquo;t receive the care they need to stay healthy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health impacts of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing maintenance</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>Buildings with maintenance issues and disrepair can harm health. Across NYC, low-income neighborhoods have a higher percentage of buildings in disrepair due to past and present disinvestment and housing discrimination. This housing disrepair harms residents&amp;rsquo; health.&#xA;No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury. All building owners are required by law to provide essential services such as heat and hot water, make timely repairs, and maintain a pest-free building.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing safety</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-safety/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health - both in terms of safety characteristics within the home, and in terms of factors that affect housing stability.&#xA;Safety characteristics A home&amp;rsquo;s safety characteristics might include:&#xA;Air conditioning, which is a vital tool to protect people who are at risk of heat-related illness and death Electric medical equipment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing stability</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/housing-stability/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health.&#xA;Housing stability In NYC, about one out of every three homes is owned by the person living there - about half the national average. Owning a home is a powerful way to build intergenerational wealth, but historical and contemporary disinvestment and housing discrimination has made it hard for many New Yorkers to own homes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indicator catalog</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/indicator-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/indicator-catalog/</guid>
      <description>Search by term, get metadata and download links.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead poisoning</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/lead/</guid>
      <description>Lead is a metal that is toxic to people. There is no safe level of lead in your body. It can cause learning and behavior problems, and delay physical growth and mental development.&#xA;In the past, it was used in gasoline, paint, ceramics, caulking, pipes and solder. In 1960, NYC banned the use of lead-based paint in homes. A national ban came into effect in 1978. Leaded gasoline was phased out beginning in the 1970&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mice and rats</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</guid>
      <description>Rats and mice are common, but preventable. In NYC, rats tend to be seen on streets, alleys and sidewalks, and in yards and basements, while mice are almost always found inside buildings.&#xA;Rats and mice thrive where there are sources of food and shelter and where property owners fail to prevent and adequately respond to their presence.&#xA;Mice, Rats and Health Today, rats are recognized for their contribution to neighborhood stress, poor quality of life, contamination of food, potential threat to public health, and for their contribution to the destruction of infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mortality</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mortality/</guid>
      <description>Death is, of course, a severe health outcome. Many deaths are preventable.&#xA;Premature mortality lets us look at deaths before age 65. It can be a useful way to indicate the overall health of the population.&#xA;Neonatal deaths, postneonatal deaths, and infant deaths let us look at deaths among the the youngest members of our communities. Infants, with new, developing bodies, can be very susceptible to environmental threats - like poisonings, accidents, and injuries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overweight</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/overweight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/overweight/</guid>
      <description>People who are overweight or obese are at increased risk for heart disease and diabetes. Physical activity and healthy eating can promote well-being and relieve stress.&#xA;Weight and the Environment Neighborhood conditions and resources can encourage or discourage healthy behaviors. The density and types of food retail outlets available in neighborhoods may affect food shopping habits and nutrition choices of residents. Healthy food choices combined with physically active lifestyle support maintenance of an optimal bodyweight and overall good health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pesticides</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/pesticides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/pesticides/</guid>
      <description>Pesticides are chemicals applied to kill or control insects, rats and mice, undesirable plants and weeds, or fungi (e.g., mold). Pesticides are often categorized by type of use (e.g., rodenticide, insecticide) or chemical class (e.g., organophosphate, pyrethroid).&#xA;Modern pesticides have been developed to have less persistence in the environment than earlier chlorine-based chemicals such as DDT. Pesticides may be applied by a commercial applicator or a non-professional who has purchased a product from a store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical activity</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/physical-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/physical-activity/</guid>
      <description>Physical activity is an important part of a healthy lifestyle. Regular physical activity is associated with many health benefits, including improved fitness, prevention of weight gain, and lower risk of heart disease, stroke, high blood pressure, diabetes and some cancers. In addition, regular physical activity and healthy eating can promote well-being and relieve stress. For children, regular physical activity is also associated with improved academic performance.&#xA;Physical Activity and the Environment Neighborhood conditions and resources can encourage or discourage healthy behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant food safety</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/restaurant-food-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/restaurant-food-safety/</guid>
      <description>New York City has approximately 28,000 restaurants that the Health Department inspects every year to monitor compliance with city and state food safety regulations. At the end of an inspection, the Health Department gives restaurants a score, which is eventually converted to a grade of A, B or C. This site describes the distribution of A grades across New York City restaurants.&#xA;Restaurant Food Safety and Health Safe food handling can protect diners from foodborne illness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social conditions</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/social-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/social-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities But when people don’t have access to these conditions, they experience worse health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transportation-related injuries</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Traffic injuries are no accident. Like other public health concerns, they are preventable through data driven solutions. In NYC, traffic injuries, which include injuries among pedestrians, bicyclists, motorcyclists, and motor vehicle occupants, are a leading cause of injury-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits.&#xA;In February 2014, NYC launched “Vision Zero”, an action plan to reduce injuries and deaths on city streets. Vision Zero is a multi-agency effort, incorporating road engineering, traffic enforcement, community outreach and education, and policy work to make NYC streets safer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vector-borne disease</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</guid>
      <description>Vectorborne diseases are diseases that are transmitted from an arthropod (usually a tick or mosquito, etc.) to humans or other animals. Some vectorborne disease agents are maintained primarily through transmission between arthropods and humans (e.g., dengue virus and malaria), while others are maintained between arthropods and animal reservoirs (e.g., Lyme disease and West Nile virus) and humans may become infected incidentally.&#xA;Vectorborne Disease and the Environment Climate is one of many important interacting variables that affect people’s risk for vectorborne diseases in New York City.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/violence/</guid>
      <description>Violence is the use of physical, verbal, and/or emotional force to injure, harm, abuse, damage, or destroy. Interpersonal violence includes child abuse and neglect, youth violence, intimate partner violence, sexual violence, and elder abuse. Violence can involve injury to self, including self-harm, suicide attempts, and death by suicide. Violence can also take the form of power against a group or community.&#xA;Violence is a public health issue because it is a cause of morbidity and mortality, leading to physical and emotional harm, an increase in negative health outcomes, premature death, psychological trauma and persistent fear to individuals and communities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weather-related illness</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worker health</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/worker-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/worker-health/</guid>
      <description>Every year in New York City, workers are injured on the job or become ill as a result of exposure to health hazards at work. However, most work-related illnesses and injuries are preventable – safer work environments can be achieved when workplace hazards are understood and appropriate prevention measures are put in place.&#xA;Data on work-related injuries and illness are used to show how often these preventable events occur and to identify factors that place workers at risk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking, driving, and cycling</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/walking-driving-and-cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/walking-driving-and-cycling/</guid>
      <description>People get around New York City in many ways - public transit, walking, cycling, driving, and other modes too. When these individual behaviors are added up, they shape our city and our health.&#xA;Our built environment influences these behaviors. The design of our streets and presence of infrastructure like bicycle lanes, well maintained sidewalks, safe street crossings, dedicated bus lanes and convenient access to the subway have the potential to increase both the usage and safety of these forms of transportation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
