<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing/</guid>
      <description>No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.
In New York City, substandard or poor housing tends to cluster in neighborhoods. Homes that are deteriorating or dilapidated, or homes near buildings with broken or boarded-up windows, disproportionately tend to be in low-income neighborhoods, although the differences for these indicators have decreased.
Housing and Health Housing quality impacts health directly and indirectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Create homes for nearly a million more New Yorkers while making housing and neighborhoods more affordable and sustainable.
Housing Supply We are tracking the number of new housing units created since the start of the plan in 2007, as well as the size of the total housing stock, to ensure that the city is meeting the supply portion of its goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social and Economic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/social-and-economic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/social-and-economic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives. They are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.
People tend to be healthier when they have access to:
 Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities  But when people don’t have access to these conditions, they experience worse health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/violence/</guid>
      <description>Violence is the use of physical, verbal, and/or emotional force to injure, harm, abuse, damage, or destroy. Interpersonal violence includes child abuse and neglect, youth violence, intimate partner violence, sexual violence, and elder abuse. Violence can involve injury to self, including self-harm, suicide attempts, and death by suicide. Violence can also take the form of power against a group or community.
Violence is a public health issue because it is a cause of morbidity and mortality, leading to physical and emotional harm, an increase in negative health outcomes, premature death, psychological trauma and persistent fear to individuals and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather-Related Illness</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
