<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pollutants on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/pollutants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pollutants on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:14:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/pollutants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The New York City Community Air Survey</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/airquality/nyccas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/airquality/nyccas/</guid>
      <description>NYCCAS Report: 2008-2022 In 2007, the New York City Department of Health and Mental Hygiene (Health Department) established the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS), the largest ongoing urban air monitoring program of any U.S. city. NYCCAS, which began collecting data in December 2008, is a collaboration between the Health Department and Queens College of the City University of New York and provides data to:&#xA;Help inform PlaNYC, the City’s sustainability plan Track changes in air quality over time Estimate exposures for health research Inform the public about local topics, such as recent air quality improvements, car-free zones, changes in the sources of air pollution, unique air quality studies conducted in New York City, efforts to reduce health impacts and differences in air quality and related health impacts across NYC neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.&#xA;Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter and ground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.&#xA;Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health impacts of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
