<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Key Topics in Environmental Health on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Key Topics in Environmental Health on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 13:58:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Child Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/childhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/childhealth/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong health can be determined by your health when you are a child. Plus, children can be fragile, and can be more harmed by environmental threats. So, ways that the environment can affect health often are particularly important for child health.
In New York City, several environmental factors play a key role in determining childhood health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social and Economic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/social/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives. They are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.
People tend to be healthier when they have access to economic and financial stability, higher education, adequate health care, healthy neighborhoods, and safe, strong communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pests and Pesticides</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/pests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/pests/</guid>
      <description>Pests and pesticides can both have health effects. Household pests like mice, rats, and cockroaches can trigger asthma, while bed bugs are a well-known nuisance. Meanwhile, warmer winters may mean more vector-borne diseases like babesiosis and west nile virus.
Pesticides are chemicals used to control or kill insects, rats, mice, plants and weeds, or fungi (mold). Esposure to pesticides can occur from consuming foods or beverages that contain pesticide residues, from direct contact with the skin or eyes, or from breathing air in areas where pesticides are applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food and Drink</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/foodanddrink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:58:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/foodanddrink/</guid>
      <description>We all make choices around food and drink, but sometimes, those choices are made for us by our food environments.
Our food environments include neighborhood-level alcohol access, unhealthy food access, and restaurant food safety. Additionally, drinking water quality data includes data on contaminants that are most frequently found at levels that may be of public health significant in the country&amp;rsquo;s drinking water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation and Active Design</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:58:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/transportation/</guid>
      <description>Physical inactivity and unhealthy diet rank among the leading risk factors for premature death in the United States. Active design, however, promotes health by using architectural and urban design strategies to encourage walking, bicycling, stair climbing, transit use, active recreation, and healthy eating.
Designing to increase access to parks, create pedestrian plazas, ensure well-maintained sidewalks, plant street trees, provide secure bicycle storage, and make stairwaus in buildings attractive and accessible can have a measurable effect on people&amp;rsquo;s ability to safetly get regular physical activity that can keep them healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/housing/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time at home - so the household environment can significantly affect health. Disrepair that stems from longterm maintenance neglect can lead to serious health problems, including: lead poisoning from lead paint; asthma and other respiratory issues triggered by pests; and carbon monoxide poisoning.
In NYC, substandard housing is disproportionately located in low-income neighborhoods, as historical disinvestment lead to severe, systemic maintenance deficiencies that threatens people&amp;rsquo;s health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate and Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/climatehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 12:33:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/climatehealth/</guid>
      <description>Climate, including extreme weather, has a direct impact on health. As NYC&amp;rsquo;s climate changes, along with the world&amp;rsquo;s climate, we expect more frequent and intense heat waves, increased rainfall and more severe storms. These will add to existing weather-related risks. Already, heat kills more people than all other natural disasters combined.
In New York City, those most vulnerable to the dangers of hot weather are older adults and people with health conditions like heart disease, diabetes, and cognitive impairment - especially those in low-income, Black, and Brown communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/airquality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 12:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/airquality/</guid>
      <description>New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, drops of liquid, gasses, and other pollution that can affect health. Bad air quality can be particularly dangerous for older adults, children, and people with heart or lung conditions.
Air quality varies from neighborhood to neighborhood, based on local levels of emissions and many other factors. We monitor air quality using the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS), NYC&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive air quality monitoring and modeling network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
