<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>childhealth on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/categories/childhealth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in childhealth on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 01:18:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/categories/childhealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Housing creates health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/housing-creates-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 01:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/housing-creates-health/</guid>
      <description>Health is determined by many factors, and people tend to be healthier when they have economic stability, live in quality housing and have access to public space and safe, connected communities. In 2020, the NYC Health Department held a series of community conversations with residents and local stakeholders across 26 neighborhoods. New Yorkers shared personal stories that illuminate their priorities for building healthier neighborhoods, healthier childhoods and more. This is one part of a three-part series on how housing, economic stability and public space create health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic stability creates health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/economic-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 09:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/economic-stability/</guid>
      <description>Health is determined by many factors, and people tend to be healthier when they have economic stability, live in quality housing and have access to public space and safe, connected communities. In 2020, the NYC Health Department held a series of community conversations with residents and local stakeholders across 26 neighborhoods. New Yorkers shared personal stories that illuminate their priorities for building healthier neighborhoods, healthier childhoods and more. This is one part of a three-part series on how housing, economic stability, and public space create health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.&#xA;Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter and ground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.&#xA;Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.&#xA;Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birth defects</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/birth-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/birth-defects/</guid>
      <description>Birth defects (also called congenital malformations) are conditions that happen when a baby does not develop normally during pregnancy. Structural defects may include missing limbs, malformed hearts, spina bifida and genetic conditions like Down Syndrome. Most birth defects happen during the first three months of pregnancy and are detected within the first year of life. Some birth defects (such as cleft lip or clubfoot) are easy to see, but others (such as heart defects or hearing loss) are found using special tests (such as x-rays, CT scans, or hearing tests).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birth outcomes</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Close to 125,000 live births occur in New York City (NYC) each year. Most babies are born healthy, but those born prematurely or with low birth weight are at greater risk of disability or death. This site tracks indicators of fetal growth and development, infant and perinatal mortality, fertility and sex ratio at birth.&#xA;Birth Outcomes and the Environment Because many genetic and lifestyle factors influence growth and development of fetuses and babies, it can be difficult for researchers to study the effects of environmental exposures on birth outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cancers in children</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</guid>
      <description>Cancer begins when cells in a part of the body start to grow out of control. There are many kinds of cancer, but they all start because of out-of-control growth of abnormal cells. Leukemia (cancer of the blood-forming cells) is the most common form of childhood cancer. There are different kinds of childhood leukemia. The most common kinds are acute lymphocytic leukemia and acute myeloid leukemia . Brain and other nervous system cancers are the second most common types of childhood cancers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon monoxide</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-incidents/</guid>
      <description>Carbon monoxide (CO) is a poisonous gas that forms when fuel or other materials are burned. It is invisible and has no odor. Even short-term exposure to high levels of carbon monoxide can be fatal. Carbon monoxide blocks oxygen transport in the body. Symptoms of mild carbon monoxide poisoning include headache, nausea, fatigue, dizziness and disorientation. Breathing high concentrations of carbon monoxide can cause somebody to lose consciousness and have permanent neurological injury - or even death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cigarette smoke</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/cigarette-smoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/cigarette-smoke/</guid>
      <description>Smoking causes over a dozen cancers, heart disease, stroke, type 2 diabetes and many other diseases; it remains a leading cause of death in New York City (NYC). On average, people who do not smoke live about 10 years longer than people who do.&#xA;Additionally, there is no safe level of exposure to secondhand smoke. Secondhand smoke causes cancer, heart disease and other illnesses in adults. Children exposed to smoke are more likely to have bronchitis, asthma attacks, ear infections, pneumonia and sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead poisoning</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-explorer/lead/</guid>
      <description>Lead is a metal that is toxic to people. There is no safe level of lead in your body. It can cause learning and behavior problems, and delay physical growth and mental development.&#xA;In the past, it was used in gasoline, paint, ceramics, caulking, pipes and solder. In 1960, NYC banned the use of lead-based paint in homes. A national ban came into effect in 1978. Leaded gasoline was phased out beginning in the 1970&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/key-topics/childhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/key-topics/childhealth/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong health can be determined by your health when you are a child. Plus, children can be fragile, and can be more harmed by environmental threats. So, ways that the environment can affect health often are particularly important for child health.&#xA;In New York City, several environmental factors play a key role in determining childhood health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why violence is a public health issue</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/violence/</guid>
      <description>Using public health to prevent violence Experiencing violence affects people in many ways. It not only causes physical injury or death, but being exposed to it can also cause emotional and psychological trauma. Violence doesn’t just affect the immediate victim, it affects their surrounding community, too.&#xA;Violence can affect people throughout their lives: it is associated with worse birth outcomes, childhood developmental delays, physical and mental illness, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of redlining</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/redlining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/redlining/</guid>
      <description>Inside the 90-year-old financial policy that harms our health In public health, we often cite structural racism to help explain health patterns in our society. But what, specifically, does this mean? A close look at the history of redlining shows this connection.&#xA;When we analyze data on the health of New Yorkers, we often find the same geographic patterns, with higher rates of preventable health conditions in high-poverty neighborhoods. For example, we&amp;rsquo;ve written about how asthma and poverty are closely connected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health, housing, and history</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/housing/</guid>
      <description>For health, place matters What determines whether or not you’re healthy? You may think about what you eat, whether you exercise, whether you smoke and your family medical history.&#xA;But you may not think about how your home affects your health - and you may not think about the factors that influence where you live. For a home to be healthy, it should be free of: Cracks Holes Leaks Smoke Pests Old, peeling paint In other words, a healthy home is a well-maintained home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why asthma is a social justice issue</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/asthma-and-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-stories/asthma-and-poverty/</guid>
      <description>Poverty affects health in many ways. In New York City, the story of asthma clearly illustrates this connection.&#xA;To understand the connection between poverty and asthma, take a look at this map of poverty rates in New York City, below. The darker the color, the more residents living in poverty.&#xA;Now, compare that to a map of emergency department visits for asthma in children age 5 to 17, below. The darker the color, the higher the rate of children visiting the emergency department with asthma.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma and the Environment</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/neighborhood-reports/asthma_and_the_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/neighborhood-reports/asthma_and_the_environment/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common lung disease and a leading cause of hospitalizations for children under 15 years old. This report provides a summary of asthma indicators by neighborhood. It also describes housing and neighborhood characteristics that can make asthma worse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/neighborhood-reports/housing_and_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/neighborhood-reports/housing_and_health/</guid>
      <description>This report provides a neighborhood summary of housing conditions and related health outcomes. It also describes population characteristics that can increase vulnerability to housing hazards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor Air and Health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/neighborhood-reports/outdoor_air_and_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/neighborhood-reports/outdoor_air_and_health/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is one of the most important environmental threats to urban populations and while all people are exposed, pollutant emissions, levels of exposure, and population vulnerability vary across neighborhoods. Exposures to common air pollutants have been linked to respiratory and cardiovascular diseases, cancers, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
