<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>exhaust on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/exhaust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in exhaust on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:14:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/exhaust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The New York City Community Air Survey</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/nyccas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/nyccas/</guid>
      <description>NYCCAS Report: 2008-2022 In 2007, the New York City Department of Health and Mental Hygiene (Health Department) established the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS), the largest ongoing urban air monitoring program of any U.S. city. NYCCAS, which began collecting data in December 2008, is a collaboration between the Health Department and Queens College of the City University of New York and provides data to:&#xA;Help inform PlaNYC, the City’s sustainability plan Track changes in air quality over time Estimate exposures for health research Inform the public about local topics, such as recent air quality improvements, car-free zones, changes in the sources of air pollution, unique air quality studies conducted in New York City, efforts to reduce health impacts and differences in air quality and related health impacts across NYC neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Air Quality: PM2.5 in NYC</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/realtime-air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 19:30:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/realtime-air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Fine particles (PM2.5) are among the most harmful pollutants. Long-term exposure to PM2.5 contributes to an estimated 2,000 excess deaths from lung and heart disease each year in NYC (1 out of every 25 deaths in NYC), and short-term exposure contributes to asthma incidents severe enough to require a trip to the emergency department, and other health threats.&#xA;The air quality in NYC is generally good and has been improving over time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Neighborhood&#39;s Air Quality</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/neighborhood-air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 12:04:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/neighborhood-air-quality/</guid>
      <description>We combine data from our air quality monitoring network, NYCCAS, with other data to understand what makes air quality in one neighborhood different from air quality in another. We found that building emissions, building density, industrial areas, and traffic density are associated with differences in air quality.&#xA;If we don&amp;rsquo;t have an air quality monitor in one neighborhood, but we know its building density, its industrial area, and its traffic, then we can model (estimate or predict) its air quality - based on monitored air quality in similar neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.&#xA;Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter and ground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.&#xA;Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health impacts of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
