<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rats on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/rats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rats on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 13:11:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/rats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why trash is a public health issue</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/sanitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 13:11:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/sanitation/</guid>
      <description>New York City’s modern history of public health starts in the 1600s with the Bureau of Sanitary Inspections, and ever since, sanitation has been an essential part of public health — fighting disease by keeping our city clean.&#xA;From A Chronology of the NYC Department of Health&#xA;How sanitation affects health Proper sanitation is a crucial component of public health and of safe, health, and equitable neighborhood environments.&#xA;Trash can pollute our soil, water, and air, becoming an issue of health, quality of life and equity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/housing/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time at home - so the household environment can significantly affect health. Disrepair that stems from long-term maintenance neglect can lead to serious health problems, including: lead poisoning from lead paint; asthma and other respiratory issues triggered by pests; and carbon monoxide poisoning.&#xA;In NYC, substandard housing is disproportionately located in low-income neighborhoods, as historical disinvestment lead to severe, systemic maintenance deficiencies that threatens people&amp;rsquo;s health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mice and rats</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/mice-and-rats/</guid>
      <description>Rats and mice are common, but preventable. In NYC, rats tend to be seen on streets and sidewalks, and in backyards and basements, while mice are almost always found inside homes.&#xA;Rats and mice thrive where there are sources of food and shelter and where property owners fail to prevent and adequately respond to their presence.&#xA;This site provides survey data on the prevalence of mice or rats inside and outside of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pesticides</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/pesticides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-explorer/pesticides/</guid>
      <description>Pesticides are chemicals applied to kill or control insects, rats and mice, undesirable plants and weeds, or fungi (e.g., mold). Pesticides are often categorized by type of use (e.g., rodenticide, insecticide) or chemical class (e.g., organophosphate, pyrethroid).&#xA;Modern pesticides have been developed to have less persistence in the environment than earlier chlorine-based chemicals such as DDT. Pesticides may be applied by a commercial applicator or a non-professional who has purchased a product from a store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pests and pesticides</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/pests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/key-topics/pests/</guid>
      <description>Pests and pesticides can both have health effects. Household pests like mice, rats, and cockroaches can trigger asthma, while bed bugs are a well-known nuisance. Meanwhile, warmer winters may mean more vector-borne diseases like babesiosis and west nile virus.&#xA;Pesticides are chemicals used to control or kill insects, rats, mice, plants and weeds, or fungi (mold). Exposure to pesticides can occur from consuming foods or beverages that contain pesticide residues, from direct contact with the skin or eyes, or from breathing air in areas where pesticides are applied.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
