<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>climate on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/climate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in climate on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate and Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/climatehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/climatehealth/</guid>
      <description>Climate, including extreme weather, has a direct impact on health. As NYC&amp;rsquo;s climate changes, along with the world&amp;rsquo;s climate, we expect more frequent and intense heat waves, increased rainfall and more severe storms. These will add to existing weather-related risks. Already, heat kills more people than all other natural disasters combined.
In New York City, those most vulnerable to the dangers of hot weather are older adults and people with health conditions like heart disease, diabetes, and cognitive impairment - especially those in low-income, Black, and Brown communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Urban Heat Island Effect in New York City</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/localtemp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/localtemp/</guid>
      <description>In New York City and across the country, more people die from extreme heat than from all other natural disasters combined. To understand how to keep New Yorkers safe from extreme heat, we studied neighborhood factors that affect temperature, and found that grass, shrubs, and trees can play a major role. Let’s take a look.
At 6.00 PM on June 30, 2018, the air temperature at the LaGuardia Airport Weather Station was 89° Fahrenheit (F).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/climate/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events like heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes.
The world’s climate is shifting, becoming warmer with more precipitation and weather extremes. Over the past century in New York City, average temperatures have increased by 0.25°F per decade, precipitation by 0.72 inches per decade, and sea levels by 1.2 inches per decade. By the 2020s, a projected 25-30 days above 90°F are expected in a typical summer, resulting in more frequent and intense heat waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/climate-change/</guid>
      <description>There is broad consensus within the scientific community that human activity is changing the Earth&amp;rsquo;s climate through increasing concentrations of greenhouse gases (GHGs) — primarily carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), nitrous oxide (N2O), and chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) — in the atmosphere.
Scientists have predicted that unless GHG emissions are substantially stemmed by the end of the century, climate change will become irreversible.
A key part of combating climate change is mitigation, which means reducing GHG emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/energy/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Reduce energy consumption and make our energy systems cleaner and more reliable. To measure progress, we are tracking how our buildings are becoming more energy efficient as well as the extent to which our energy is becoming cleaner and more reliable.
Cleaner Energy To determine whether energy in NYC is getting cleaner, we track the carbon intensity of our electricity supply using a measure called an emissions coefficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting New Yorkers from extreme heat</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/heat/</guid>
      <description>Hot weather is dangerous. In New York City and across the country, more people on average die from extreme heat each year than from all other natural disasters.
Heat stress happens when your body’s temperature increases quickly. When the body can no longer control its temperature or cool itself down, it can lead to death.
At the NYC Health Department, we track heat stress deaths by reviewing causes of death recorded by the Bureau of Vital Statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
