<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>built environments on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/built-environments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in built environments on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:59:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/built-environments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:59:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>Our neighborhoods are the world around us. The build environment and the social environment where we spend most of our time affect health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing/</guid>
      <description>No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.
In New York City, substandard or poor housing tends to cluster in neighborhoods. Homes that are deteriorating or dilapidated, or homes near buildings with broken or boarded-up windows, disproportionately tend to be in low-income neighborhoods, although the differences for these indicators have decreased.
Housing and Health Housing quality impacts health directly and indirectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Create homes for nearly a million more New Yorkers while making housing and neighborhoods more affordable and sustainable.
Housing Supply We are tracking the number of new housing units created since the start of the plan in 2007, as well as the size of the total housing stock, to ensure that the city is meeting the supply portion of its goal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
