<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lead on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/lead/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lead on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 08:29:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/lead/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lead poisoning affects adults too</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/adult-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 08:29:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/adult-lead/</guid>
      <description>Lead is a harmful metal that can cause serious health issues. When lead poisoning makes headlines, the focus is usually on children’s health: Kids are at higher risk for lead exposure, which can cause developmental, learning and behavior issues.&#xA;But lead can also harm adults. In adults, lead can cause increased blood pressure, kidney and brain problems, infertility and impotence. During pregnancy, lead exposure can cause miscarriage or babies to be born too soon or too small.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/key-topics/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/key-topics/housing/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time at home - so the household environment can significantly affect health. Disrepair that stems from long-term maintenance neglect can lead to serious health problems, including: lead poisoning from lead paint; asthma and other respiratory issues triggered by pests; and carbon monoxide poisoning.&#xA;In NYC, substandard housing is disproportionately located in low-income neighborhoods, as historical disinvestment lead to severe, systemic maintenance deficiencies that threatens people&amp;rsquo;s health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead poisoning</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/lead/</guid>
      <description>Lead is a metal that is toxic to people. There is no safe level of lead in your body. It can cause learning and behavior problems, and delay physical growth and mental development.&#xA;In the past, it was used in gasoline, paint, ceramics, caulking, pipes and solder. In 1960, NYC banned the use of lead-based paint in homes. A national ban came into effect in 1978. Leaded gasoline was phased out beginning in the 1970&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/key-topics/childhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/key-topics/childhealth/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong health can be determined by your health when you are a child. Plus, children can be fragile, and can be more harmed by environmental threats. So, ways that the environment can affect health often are particularly important for child health.&#xA;In New York City, several environmental factors play a key role in determining childhood health.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
