<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>safety on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in safety on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:59:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:59:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>Our neighborhoods are the world around us. The built environment and the social environment where we spend most of our time affect health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Create homes for nearly a million more New Yorkers while making housing and neighborhoods more affordable and sustainable.
Housing Supply We are tracking the number of new housing units created since the start of the plan in 2007, as well as the size of the total housing stock, to ensure that the city is meeting the supply portion of its goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant Food Safety</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/restaurant-food-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/restaurant-food-safety/</guid>
      <description>New York City has approximately 24,000 restaurants that the Health Department inspects every year to monitor compliance with city and state food safety regulations. At the end of an inspection, the Health Department gives restaurants a score, which is eventually converted to a grade of A, B or C. This site describes the distribution of A grades across New York City restaurants.
Restaurant Food Safety and Health Safe food handling can protect diners from foodborne illness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/traffic/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Expand sustainable transportation choices and ensure the reliability and quality of our transportation network.
To measure progress towards this goal, we are tracking the switch to more sustainable modes of transportation (modal shift) and mass transit capacity, as well as whether our transportation system is meeting a state of good repair.
Modal Shift We are tracking the extent to which people are using non-automobile modes of transit including public transportation (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation-related Injuries</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Traffic injuries are no accident. Like other public health concerns, they are preventable through data driven solutions. In NYC, traffic injuries, which include injuries among pedestrians, bicyclists, motorcyclists, and motor vehicle occupants, are a leading cause of injury-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits.
In February 2014, NYC launched “Vision Zero”, an action plan to reduce injuries and deaths on city streets. Vision Zero is a multi-agency effort, incorporating road engineering, traffic enforcement, community outreach and education, and policy work to make NYC streets safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking, Driving, and Cycling</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/walking-driving-and-cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/walking-driving-and-cycling/</guid>
      <description>None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environments matter: the road to street safety in NYC</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 10:54:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 public health emergency has changed New York City in many ways - including how we get around the city. As the city continues to adapt to COVID-19, New Yorkers will look for ways to get around that feel safe - redistributing transit among different modes to ease crowding and increase safety on public transportation. As more New Yorkers use bicycles, let&#39;s take a look at safety on our streets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
