<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neighborhoods on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/neighborhoods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in neighborhoods on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 19:30:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/neighborhoods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Air Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/airquality/realtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 19:30:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/airquality/realtime/</guid>
      <description>NYC&amp;rsquo;s air quality is generally good and has been improving over time. But hour to hour, there&amp;rsquo;s large variation in our air quality - even in neighborhoods with the cleanest air. That means that for short periods, some New Yorkers are exposed to high levels of pollutants.
Fine particles (PM2.5) are among the most harmful pollutants. Long-term exposure to PM2.5 contributes to an estimated 2,300 excess deaths from lung and heart disease each year in NYC (1 out of every 20 deaths in NYC), and short-term exposure contributes to asthma incidents severe enough to require a trip to the emergency department, as well as other health threats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:59:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>Our neighborhoods are the world around us. The build environment and the social environment where we spend most of our time affect health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Neighborhood&#39;s Air Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/airquality/aqe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 12:04:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/airquality/aqe/</guid>
      <description>We combine data from our air quality monitoring network, NYCCAS, with other data to understand what makes one neighborhood&amp;rsquo;s air quality different from another&amp;rsquo;s. We found that building emissions, building density, industrial areas, and traffic density are associated with differences in air quality.
If we don&amp;rsquo;t have an air quality monitor in one neighborhood, but we know its building density, its industrial area, and its traffic, then we can model (estimate or predict) its air quality - based on monitored air quality in similar neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol Access</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/alcohol-access/</guid>
      <description>Heavy regular drinking and binge drinking contribute to a wide range of chronic health problems, including heart disease, diabetes, cancer, stroke, cirrhosis, depression and dementia. Alcohol use is also associated with suicide, homicide, domestic violence, sexually transmitted diseases and injuries. It is one of the leading behavior-related causes of death in New York City (NYC).
This site provides data on heavy alcohol consumption and alcohol outlets in NYC.
Alcohol and the Environment Greater alcohol outlet density has been associated with a variety of health and social consequences, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing/</guid>
      <description>No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.
In New York City, substandard or poor housing tends to cluster in neighborhoods. Homes that are deteriorating or dilapidated, or homes near buildings with broken or boarded-up windows, disproportionately tend to be in low-income neighborhoods, although the differences for these indicators have decreased.
Housing and Health Housing quality impacts health directly and indirectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing and Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/housing-and-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Create homes for nearly a million more New Yorkers while making housing and neighborhoods more affordable and sustainable.
Housing Supply We are tracking the number of new housing units created since the start of the plan in 2007, as well as the size of the total housing stock, to ensure that the city is meeting the supply portion of its goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noise</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/noise/</guid>
      <description>Ambient noise is sound from an environmental source, such as traffic, construction, industrial or recreation activities, animals, or people’s voices, that is unwanted to the person who hears it.
Noise and the Environment Exposure to any noise has long been recognized as an important occupational health hazard in workplaces and is increasingly viewed as a prevalent urban environmental hazard associated with adverse psychosocial and physiologic health effects such as sleep disturbance, higher blood pressure, cardiovascular disease, and impaired cognitive performance in children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parks and Public Space</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/parks-and-public-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/parks-and-public-space/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Ensure that all New Yorkers live within a ten minute walk of a park.
Park Distance To be sure that nearly everyone is within a ten minute walk, we are tracking the numbers of New Yorkers who live within both a ½ and a ¼ mile of a park. These distances were chosen because people walk at different speeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/violence/</guid>
      <description>Violence is the use of physical, verbal, and/or emotional force to injure, harm, abuse, damage, or destroy. Interpersonal violence includes child abuse and neglect, youth violence, intimate partner violence, sexual violence, and elder abuse. Violence can involve injury to self, including self-harm, suicide attempts, and death by suicide. Violence can also take the form of power against a group or community.
Violence is a public health issue because it is a cause of morbidity and mortality, leading to physical and emotional harm, an increase in negative health outcomes, premature death, psychological trauma and persistent fear to individuals and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why violence is a public health issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/violence/</guid>
      <description>Using public health to prevent violence    Experiencing violence affects people in many ways. It not only causes physical injury or death, but being exposed to it can also cause emotional and psychological trauma. Violence doesn’t just affect the immediate victim, it affects their surrounding community, too. Violence can affect people throughout their lives: it is associated with worse birth outcomes, childhood developmental delays, physical and mental illness, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood boundaries on the EH Data Portal</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/geographies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/geographies/</guid>
      <description>New York City has hundreds of neighborhoods and nearly as many ways of drawing neighborhood boundaries. When you visit the Environment &amp;amp; Health Data Portal, you might notice that data is available in several different neighborhood schemes.
For example, dig around in the asthma data pages and you&amp;rsquo;ll find Adults with Asthma presented by UHF34 neighborhoods, Public School Children with Asthma presented by UHF42 neighborhoods, and Asthma emergency department visits are offered by NTAs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
