<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health equity on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://stgbespweb600/IndicatorPublic/beta/keywords/health-equity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health equity on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:23:23 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stgbespweb600/IndicatorPublic/beta/keywords/health-equity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Efforts to reduce air pollution should focus on neighborhoods with the worst health impacts.</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-stories/hia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:23:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600/IndicatorPublic/beta/data-stories/hia/</guid>
      <description>Every year in NYC between 2015 and 2017 (the most recent years for which this analysis is available), fine particulate matter pollution from motor vehicles and burning fossil fuels caused:
At least 2,000 deaths About 1,400 hospital admissions for lung and heart conditions 3,750 emergency department admissions for asthma Since air pollution causes significant illness and death in New York City, it&amp;rsquo;s important to reduce air pollution. So where do we start?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inequality and health inequities</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 07:59:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/social/</guid>
      <description>Inequality is a significant driver of bad health: a society that deprives people of resources to stay healthy is a society where many people become sick, injured, or die because of factors outside of their control.
People tend to be healthier when they have access to economic and financial stability, higher education, adequate health care, healthy neighborhoods, and safe, strong communities.
Health inequities are systematic differences in health outcomes that result from differences in access to the conditions that keep people healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
