<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>air pollution on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/air-pollution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in air pollution on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:23:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/keywords/air-pollution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Efforts to reduce air pollution should focus on neighborhoods with the worst health impacts</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/hia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:23:23 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/hia/</guid>
      <description>This story was recently updated with new data.&#xA;Every year in NYC between 2017 and 2019 (The most recent data available. See all recorded years of health impacts data here), fine particulate matter pollution from motor vehicles and burning fossil fuels caused:&#xA;At least 1,800 deaths About 900 hospital admissions for lung and heart conditions 3,100 emergency department admissions for asthma Since air pollution causes significant illness and death in New York City, it&amp;rsquo;s important to reduce air pollution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZAPPA: A tool to understand air quality policies</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/zappa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/zappa/</guid>
      <description>New York City’s air quality is generally good and has been improving over time. Still, air pollution threatens health: two pollutants, ozone and PM2.5 cause about 2,400 deaths per year in NYC, and thousands more emergency department visits and hospitalizations for asthma, heart, and lung problems.&#xA;It’s important to clean up the air to protect New Yorkers, and we know how to do it: reduce emissions from buildings, vehicles, restaurants, power plants, and other sources of pollutants.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An update on air quality during COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/air-quality-and-covid-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/air-quality-and-covid-part-2/</guid>
      <description>On March 20, 2020, New York State announced the COVID-19 shutdown, officially known as NY Pause. In NYC, it lasted until June 8, 2020.&#xA;With stay-at-home orders in NY and other states, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air quality changed significantly. Earlier, we looked at data collected from real-time air pollution monitors to see how day-to-day pollution changed when people started to stay home.&#xA;More recently, we used data from our network of air quality monitors to examine air pollution changes over time and across neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking changes in New York City&#39;s sources of air pollution</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/restaurants-and-air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 12:02:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/restaurants-and-air-quality/</guid>
      <description>As city life changes, so does its air quality, as sources of emissions that affect the city&amp;rsquo;s outdoor air quality, like truck traffic, building boilers and restaurants, also change. For more than a decade, we have been tracking air quality through the NYC Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) and exploring the factors that drive neighborhood differences. We have found some interesting changes in the sources of air pollution across NYC neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Public Health Impacts of PM2.5 from Traffic Air Pollution</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/traffic-and-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 08:49:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/traffic-and-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>PM2.5—or fine particulate matter—are tiny particles that pollute the air and result from everyday urban activities like driving. PM2.5 can be solid or liquid in form when it is airborne. PM2.5 is the most harmful air pollution for humans to breathe in because the particles are small enough to enter the bloodstream through the lungs. Each PM2.5 particle is less than 2.5 microns in diameter. That is small enough to fit inside a red blood cell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality during COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/air-quality-and-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/air-quality-and-covid/</guid>
      <description>What happens when NYC stays home? The COVID-19 pandemic upended the lives of all New Yorkers. The outbreak has affected many aspects of our daily life, but there are also less apparent effects, such as impacts on our environment.&#xA;The NYC Community Air Survey uses air quality monitors to take hourly measurements of fine particulate (PM2.5) at a few sites around the city.&#xA;Generally, locations around the city see changes in PM2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality snapshots: special findings from 10 years of NYCCAS</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/air-quality-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:37:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/air-quality-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Skip Nav A traffic health threat: air toxics Noise levels that harm health The benefits of cleaner fuel Special monitoring for environmental justice For 10 years, the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) has measured air quality at 100 locations around NYC. We’ve combined these measurements with data on things related to air quality - like traffic, building emissions, green space, and much more - to model seasonal air quality in every New York City neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality in car-free areas</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/car-free-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/car-free-zones/</guid>
      <description>Does the air improve in car-free zones? People often ask us this, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great question. To answer, we turn to the NYC Community Air Survey, or NYCCAS. NYCCAS is our network of air quality monitors around the city.&#xA;NYCCAS monitors air with nearly 100 sensors across the city We use these monitors to measure levels of six different pollutants: fine particles (PM2.5), nitrogen dioxide (NO2), nitric oxide (NO), sulfur dioxide (SO2), ozone (O3), and black carbon (BC).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What our air quality monitors tell us about NYC&#39;s neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/air-quality-by-neighborhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 13:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/air-quality-by-neighborhood/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, we looked at data from the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) - a network of about 100 air quality monitors - to see if air quality improves in areas that go car-free. And the answer is yes.&#xA;NYCCAS tells us that more traffic means more air pollution nearby. So, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t have a nearby monitor, we can predict that an area that goes car-free (like Park Drive in Prospect Park, for example) sees an improvement in air quality.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
