<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>climate on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/climate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in climate on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waterways</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/waterways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/waterways/</guid>
      <description>Healthy waterways are important for both aquatic life and humans who use the water for recreation.&#xA;We measure the quality of harbor water through two key indicators:&#xA;Dissolved oxygen is essential for most aquatic life. Coastal habitats and ecosystems thrive in environments with high concentrations of dissolved oxygen.&#xA;Concentrations of fecal coliform bacteria and Enterococci bacteria. Higher levels of these bacteria can mean there is sewage-related water pollution. Though most of these bacteria do not cause disease, higher concentrations can indicate the presence of pathogenic (disease-producing) bacteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staying safe in cold weather</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 13:11:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/cold/</guid>
      <description>Cold weather can be dangerous. Here are some tips for staying safe this winter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate and health</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/key-topics/climatehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/key-topics/climatehealth/</guid>
      <description>Climate, including extreme weather, has a direct impact on health. As NYC&amp;rsquo;s climate changes, along with the world&amp;rsquo;s climate, we expect more frequent and intense heat waves, increased rainfall and more severe storms. These will add to existing weather-related risks. Already, heat kills more people than all other natural disasters combined.&#xA;In New York City, those most vulnerable to the dangers of hot weather are older adults and people with health conditions like heart disease, diabetes, and cognitive impairment - especially those in low-income, Black, and Brown communities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/heat-report-archive/2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/heat-report-archive/2021/</guid>
      <description>Summary: Heat Stress Deaths Each summer from 2010-2019, there were, on average,10 heat stress deaths (those caused directly by heat) in New York City (NYC). Lack of home air conditioning (AC) continues to be an important risk factor for heat stress death. Among those who died from heat stress, the place of death was most often an un-air-conditioned home. Black New Yorkers are more likely to die from heat stress, with death rates two times higher than among other New Yorkers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/heat-report-archive/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/heat-report-archive/2022/</guid>
      <description>Summary Each summer, an estimated 370 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May - September. Of the 370 deaths:&#xA;From 2011-2020, there was an average of 10 heat-stress deaths (caused directly by heat). From 2011-2019, there was an average of about 360 heat-exacerbated deaths (caused indirectly by heat aggravating an underlying illness).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/heat-report-archive/2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/heat-report-archive/2023/</guid>
      <description>Summary Each summer, on average, an estimated 350 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May through September. Of the 350 deaths: From 2012-2021, there were an average of 7 heat-stress deaths (caused directly by heat). From 2016-2020, there were an average of about 345 heat-exacerbated deaths (caused indirectly by heat aggravating an underlying illness).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/heat-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/heat-report/</guid>
      <description>Each summer, on average, an estimated 350 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May through September.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The urban heat island effect in NYC</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/urban-heat-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/urban-heat-island/</guid>
      <description>In New York City and across the country, more people die from extreme heat than from all other natural disasters combined. To understand how to keep New Yorkers safe from extreme heat, we studied neighborhood factors that affect temperature, and found that grass, shrubs, and trees can play a major role. Let’s take a look.&#xA;At 6.00 PM on June 30, 2018, the air temperature at the LaGuardia Airport Weather Station was 89° Fahrenheit (F).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/climate/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events like heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes.&#xA;The world’s climate is shifting, becoming warmer with more precipitation and weather extremes. Over the past century in New York City, average temperatures have increased by 0.25°F per decade, precipitation by 0.72 inches per decade, and sea levels by 1.2 inches per decade. By the 2020s, a projected 25-30 days above 90°F are expected in a typical summer, resulting in more frequent and intense heat waves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting New Yorkers from extreme heat</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/heat/</guid>
      <description>Hot weather is dangerous. In New York City and across the country, more people on average die from extreme heat each year than from all other natural disasters.&#xA;Heat stress happens when your body’s temperature increases quickly. When the body can no longer control its temperature or cool itself down, it can lead to death.&#xA;At the NYC Health Department, we track heat stress deaths by reviewing causes of death recorded by the Bureau of Vital Statistics.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
