<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>asthma on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/asthma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in asthma on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:34:38 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/keywords/asthma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Power Outages Affect Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/poweroutages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:34:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/poweroutages/</guid>
      <description>Imagine your child has asthma. One summer night, a powerful storm rolls in and knocks the power out.
Your child starts to have trouble breathing. Usually, you’d use a home nebulizer, an electric machine that turns liquid medicine into a mist that your child breathes in through a face mask.
But the power is out. Without the nebulizer, your child’s breathing gets worse - and you wonder, is it time to go to the hospital again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/airquality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 12:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/airquality/</guid>
      <description>New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, drops of liquid, gasses, and other pollution that can affect health. Bad air quality can be particularly dangerous for older adults, children, and people with heart or lung conditions.
Air quality varies from neighborhood to neighborhood, based on local levels of emissions and many other factors. We monitor air quality using the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS), NYC&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive air quality monitoring and modeling network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/housing/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time at home - so the household environment can significantly affect health. Disrepair that stems from longterm maintenance neglect can lead to serious health problems, including: lead poisoning from lead paint; asthma and other respiratory issues triggered by pests; and carbon monoxide poisoning.
In NYC, substandard housing is disproportionately located in low-income neighborhoods, as historical disinvestment lead to severe, systemic maintenance deficiencies that threatens people&amp;rsquo;s health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/air-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/air-quality/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.
Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter andground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.
Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Impacts of Air Pollution</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large City Air Quality Comparison</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/large-city-air-quality-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/large-city-air-quality-comparison/</guid>
      <description>OneNYC is a comprehensive sustainability plan for New York City&amp;rsquo;s future.
Goal: Achieve the cleanest air quality of any big United States (US) city.
To measure progress towards this goal, we are tracking atmospheric concentrations of fine particulate matter (PM 2.5) in NYC compared to other large cities (populations greater than 1 million) in the US.
Air Quality and Sustainability Particulate matter is a complex mixture of very small solids and droplets suspended in air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/childhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/childhealth/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong health can be determined by your health when you are a child. Plus, children can be fragile, and can be more harmed by environmental threats. So, ways that the environment can affect health often are particularly important for child health.
In New York City, several environmental factors play a key role in determining childhood health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of redlining</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/redlining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/redlining/</guid>
      <description>Inside the 90-year-old financial policy that harms our health In public health, we often cite structural racism to help explain health patterns in our society. But what, specifically, does this mean? A close look at the history of redlining shows this connection.
When we analyze data on the health of New Yorkers, we often find the same geographic patterns, with higher rates of preventable health conditions in high-poverty neighborhoods. For example, we&amp;rsquo;ve written about how asthma and poverty are closely connected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health, housing, and history</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/housing/</guid>
      <description>For health, place matters What determines whether or not you’re healthy? You may think about what you eat, whether you exercise, whether you smoke and your family medical history.
But you may not think about how your home affects your health - and you may not think about the factors that influence where you live. For a home to be healthy, it should be free of:  Cracks Holes Leaks Smoke Pests Old, peeling paint  In other words, a healthy home is a well-maintained home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breathe easy: NYC&#39;s air quality is improving</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/breatheeasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/breatheeasy/</guid>
      <description>The air we breathe can have a major effect on our health — air pollution can make asthma worse and can cause heart disease, lung disease, strokes, and even cancer.
Fortunately, New York City has made great strides in recent years to improve air quality. Let’s take a look.
  !function () { &#34;use strict&#34;; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function (a) { if (void 0 !== a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;]) for (var e in a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;]) { var t = document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why asthma is a social justice issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/povasthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/povasthma/</guid>
      <description>Poverty affects health in many ways. In New York City, the story of asthma clearly illustrates this connection.
To understand the connection between poverty and asthma, take a look at this map of poverty rates in New York City, below. The darker the color, the more residents living in poverty.
  !function () { &#34;use strict&#34;; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function (a) { if (void 0 !== a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;]) for (var e in a.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
