<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>report on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/keywords/report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in report on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:14:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/keywords/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The New York City Community Air Survey</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/nyccas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/nyccas/</guid>
      <description>NYCCAS Report: 2008-2022 In 2007, the New York City Department of Health and Mental Hygiene (Health Department) established the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS), the largest ongoing urban air monitoring program of any U.S. city. NYCCAS, which began collecting data in December 2008, is a collaboration between the Health Department and Queens College of the City University of New York and provides data to:&#xA;Help inform PlaNYC, the City’s sustainability plan Track changes in air quality over time Estimate exposures for health research Inform the public about local topics, such as recent air quality improvements, car-free zones, changes in the sources of air pollution, unique air quality studies conducted in New York City, efforts to reduce health impacts and differences in air quality and related health impacts across NYC neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/heat-report-archive/2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/heat-report-archive/2021/</guid>
      <description>Summary: Heat Stress Deaths Each summer from 2010-2019, there were, on average,10 heat stress deaths (those caused directly by heat) in New York City (NYC). Lack of home air conditioning (AC) continues to be an important risk factor for heat stress death. Among those who died from heat stress, the place of death was most often an un-air-conditioned home. Black New Yorkers are more likely to die from heat stress, with death rates two times higher than among other New Yorkers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/heat-report-archive/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/heat-report-archive/2022/</guid>
      <description>Summary Each summer, an estimated 370 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May - September. Of the 370 deaths:&#xA;From 2011-2020, there was an average of 10 heat-stress deaths (caused directly by heat). From 2011-2019, there was an average of about 360 heat-exacerbated deaths (caused indirectly by heat aggravating an underlying illness).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/heat-report-archive/2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/heat-report-archive/2023/</guid>
      <description>Summary Each summer, on average, an estimated 350 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May through September. Of the 350 deaths: From 2012-2021, there were an average of 7 heat-stress deaths (caused directly by heat). From 2016-2020, there were an average of about 345 heat-exacerbated deaths (caused indirectly by heat aggravating an underlying illness).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 NYC Heat-Related Mortality Report</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/heat-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:14:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-stage/data-features/heat-report/</guid>
      <description>Each summer, on average, an estimated 350 New Yorkers die prematurely because of hot weather in New York City (NYC). These heat-related deaths account for about 2% of all deaths over the warm season months of May through September.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
