<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>justice on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/justice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in justice on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 13:11:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why trash is a public health issue</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/sanitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 13:11:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/sanitation/</guid>
      <description>New York City’s modern history of public health starts in the 1600s with the Bureau of Sanitary Inspections, and ever since, sanitation has been an essential part of public health — fighting disease by keeping our city clean.&#xA;From A Chronology of the NYC Department of Health&#xA;How sanitation affects health Proper sanitation is a crucial component of public health and of safe, health, and equitable neighborhood environments.&#xA;Trash can pollute our soil, water, and air, becoming an issue of health, quality of life and equity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A walk through history</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/block-by-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 08:49:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/block-by-block/</guid>
      <description>A neighborhood is not only shaped by its residents, but also by governmental practices and policies. Some of these have discriminated against residents because of the color of their skin and have segregated neighborhoods across the nation - including in New York City. This timeline is a selection of key processes and policies that shaped the physical environment and population of East Harlem, and some of the efforts to respond to local issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Displacement Risk</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/displacement-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-features/displacement-risk/</guid>
      <description>Housing stability creates health, but in NYC, many people have difficulty accessing healthy, stable housing.&#xA;In some neighborhoods, residents at are higher risk of being displaced - forced to leave their homes, and their neighborhoods, due combinations of market pressure, rent burden, housing conditions, poverty, and injustice in the housing market.&#xA;To show people&amp;rsquo;s risk of being forced out of their homes or neighborhoods, the Department of City Planning and the Department of Housing Preservation and Development created a Displacement Risk Index, part of the Equitable Development Data Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inequality and health inequities</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/key-topics/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 07:59:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/key-topics/social/</guid>
      <description>Inequality is a significant driver of bad health: a society that deprives people of resources to stay healthy is a society where many people become sick, injured, or die because of factors outside of their control.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to economic and financial stability, higher education, adequate health care, healthy neighborhoods, and safe, strong communities.&#xA;Health inequities are systematic differences in health outcomes that result from differences in access to the conditions that keep people healthy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic conditions</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities Access to these are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social conditions</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/social-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/social-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities But when people don’t have access to these conditions, they experience worse health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/violence/</guid>
      <description>Violence is the use of physical, verbal, and/or emotional force to injure, harm, abuse, damage, or destroy. Interpersonal violence includes child abuse and neglect, youth violence, intimate partner violence, sexual violence, and elder abuse. Violence can involve injury to self, including self-harm, suicide attempts, and death by suicide. Violence can also take the form of power against a group or community.&#xA;Violence is a public health issue because it is a cause of morbidity and mortality, leading to physical and emotional harm, an increase in negative health outcomes, premature death, psychological trauma and persistent fear to individuals and communities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air quality snapshots: special findings from 10 years of NYCCAS</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/air-quality-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:37:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-stories/air-quality-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Skip Nav A traffic health threat: air toxics Noise levels that harm health The benefits of cleaner fuel Special monitoring for environmental justice For 10 years, the New York City Community Air Survey (NYCCAS) has measured air quality at 100 locations around NYC. We’ve combined these measurements with data on things related to air quality - like traffic, building emissions, green space, and much more - to model seasonal air quality in every New York City neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
