<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>childhealth on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/childhealth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in childhealth on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/childhealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Child Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/childhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:59:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key_topics/childhealth/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong health can be determined by your health when you are a child. Plus, children can be fragile, and can be more harmed by environmental threats. So, ways that the environment can affect health often are particularly important for child health.
In New York City, several environmental factors play a key role in determining childhood health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/asthma_mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:38:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/asthma_mm/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air quality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/airquality_mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:03:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_explorer/airquality_mm/</guid>
      <description>Air quality is a measure of the condition of the air around us. The less air pollution there is, the better the air quality.
Like many cities, New York City&amp;rsquo;s air contains particles, liquid droplets, gases, and other contaminants that could impact health. Two pollutants, particulate matter and ground-level ozone, are of particular health concern.
Although New York City&amp;rsquo;s air does not currently meet federal air quality standards, it has improved significantly over the past two decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Asthma is a Social Justice Issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/povasthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 12:44:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data_stories/povasthma/</guid>
      <description>Poverty can affect how you breathe Poverty affects health in many ways. In New York City, the story of asthma clearly illustrates this connection.
To understand the connection between poverty and asthma, take a look at this map of poverty rates in New York City, below. The darker the color, the more residents living in poverty.
raw HTML within.  Now, compare that to a map of emergency department visits for asthma in children age 5 to 17, below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>