<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>heat-related illness on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/keywords/heat-related-illness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in heat-related illness on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/keywords/heat-related-illness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate and health</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 12:33:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/</guid>
      <description>Climate, including extreme weather, has a direct impact on health. As NYC&amp;rsquo;s climate changes, along with the world&amp;rsquo;s climate, we expect more frequent and intense heat waves, increased rainfall and more severe storms. These will add to existing weather-related risks. Already, heat kills more people than all other natural disasters combined.
In New York City, those most vulnerable to the dangers of hot weather are older adults and people with health conditions like heart disease, diabetes, and cognitive impairment - especially those in low-income, Black, and Brown communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time heat-related illness</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/syndromic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 11:51:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/syndromic/</guid>
      <description>Extreme heat is dangerous. It can cause illness, make chronic conditions worse, and even kill. Heat-related illnesses happen when the body cannot cool down enough. These include:
Heat exhaustion Muscle cramps Fainting Heat stroke, the most serious form of heat-related illness Heat can also exacerbate chronic conditions, such as cardiovascular diseases or kidney conditions. These conditions may not be recognized or labeled as heat-related in a medical record but can be assessed using statistical models and are another a negative health outcome related to heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Heat Vulnerability Index</title>
      <link>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/hvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:49:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stgbespweb600.health.dohmh.nycnet/IndicatorPublic/beta/key-topics/climatehealth/hvi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
