<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>healthoutcomes on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/healthoutcomes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in healthoutcomes on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:34:38 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/categories/healthoutcomes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Power Outages Affect Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/poweroutages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:34:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/poweroutages/</guid>
      <description>Imagine your child has asthma. One summer night, a powerful storm rolls in and knocks the power out.
Your child starts to have trouble breathing. Usually, you’d use a home nebulizer, an electric machine that turns liquid medicine into a mist that your child breathes in through a face mask.
But the power is out. Without the nebulizer, your child’s breathing gets worse - and you wonder, is it time to go to the hospital again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health outcomes</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/healthoutcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 12:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/key-topics/healthoutcomes/</guid>
      <description>Our environment - the world around us - affects our health. Here are datasets on the effects that our environment has on our health - the health outcomes we experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthma is a common disease in which the lungs become swollen, making breathing difficult. Symptoms include wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath and tightness in the chest. The exact causes of asthma are not known. Asthma cannot be cured, but it can be controlled.
Asthma is a leading cause of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and missed school days in New York City&amp;rsquo;s poorest neighborhoods. In NYC, asthma is more common among low-income Black and Latino children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth Defects</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-defects/</guid>
      <description>Birth defects (also called congenital malformations) are conditions that happen when a baby does not develop normally during pregnancy. Structural defects may include missing limbs, malformed hearts, spina bifida and genetic conditions like Down syndrome. Most birth defects happen during the first three months of pregnancy and are detected within the first year of life. Some birth defects (such as cleft lip or clubfoot) are easy to see, but others (such as heart defects or hearing loss) are found using special tests (such as x-rays, CT scans, or hearing tests).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/birth-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Close to 125,000 live births occur in New York City (NYC) each year. Most babies are born healthy, but those born prematurely or with low birth weight are at greater risk of disability or death. This site tracks indicators of fetal growth and development, infant and perinatal mortality, fertility and sex ratio at birth.
Birth Outcomes and the Environment Because many genetic and lifestyle factors influence growth and development of fetuses and babies, it can be difficult for researchers to study the effects of environmental exposures on birth outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancer/</guid>
      <description>Cancer is the general name for a group of more than 100 diseases in which cells in a part of the body begin to grow out of control. Cancers are named for the organ or type of cell in which they start.
Cancer occurs at all ages, but the risk increases with age. One of every two men, and one of every three women, will be diagnosed with cancer at some time in their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancers in Children</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/cancers-in-children/</guid>
      <description>Cancer begins when cells in a part of the body start to grow out of control. There are many kinds of cancer, but they all start because of out-of-control growth of abnormal cells. Leukemia (cancer of the blood-forming cells) is the most common form of childhood cancer. There are different kinds of childhood leukemia. The most common kinds are acute lymphocytic leukemia (ALL) and acute myeloid leukemia (AML). Brain and other nervous system cancers are the second most common types of childhood cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Monoxide Poisoning</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/carbon-monoxide-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>Carbon monoxide (CO) is a poisonous gas that forms when fuel or other materials are burned. It is invisible and has no odor. Even short-term exposure to high levels of carbon monoxide can be fatal.
This site contains data on unintentional carbon monoxide incidents and emergency responses by the New York City Fire Department (FDNY), reports to the NYC Poison Control Center (PCC) of actual or potential carbon monoxide exposure and hospitalizations of NYC residents who have been poisoned by carbon monoxide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease/</guid>
      <description>More information coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falls Among Older Adults</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/falls-among-older-adults/</guid>
      <description>Each year, one in three older adults (65 years and older) falls. Among New York City&amp;rsquo;s older adults, there are approximately 30,500 emergency department (ED) visits, 16,600 hospitalizations, and 300 deaths each year. Falls are not a normal part of aging, and research shows that many falls can be prevented.
Falls and the environment Although falls can occur anywhere, falls among older adults frequently happen at home. More than one-half of fall-related hospitalizations among older adults were due to falls in the home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Impacts of Air Pollution</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/health-impacts-of-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution is an important environmental threat to the health of New York City residents. Exposures to two common air pollutants, fine particulate matter (PM2.5) and ozone (O3), can worsen respiratory illness and heart conditions and contribute to premature deaths. Older adults, children and people with existing heart and lung disease are especially affected. This site provides estimates of the impact of air pollution on the health of NYC residents as measured by the numbers of emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths attributable to PM2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Attacks</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/heart-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/heart-attacks/</guid>
      <description>A heart attack is referred to medically as an acute myocardial infarction. It is caused when the blood flow that brings oxygen to the heart is severely reduced or cut off altogether. Without adequate blood flow, heart cells can quickly become injured or die. Most heart attacks are an acute event that follows years of atherosclerosis - a build up of plaque in the arteries around the heart. Factors in the environment may contribute to both atherosclerosis and to the acute event itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/mortality/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overweight</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/overweight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/overweight/</guid>
      <description>People who are overweight or obese are at increased risk for heart disease and diabetes. Physical activity and healthy eating can promote well-being and relieve stress.
Weight and the Environment Neighborhood conditions and resources can encourage or discourage healthy behaviors. The density and types of food retail outlets available in neighborhoods may affect food shopping habits and nutrition choices of residents. Healthy food choices combined with physically active lifestyle support maintenance of an optimal bodyweight and overall good health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transportation-related Injuries</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/transportation-related-injuries/</guid>
      <description>Traffic injuries are no accident. Like other public health concerns, they are preventable through data driven solutions. In NYC, traffic injuries, which include injuries among pedestrians, bicyclists, motorcyclists, and motor vehicle occupants, are a leading cause of injury-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits.
In February 2014, NYC launched “Vision Zero”, an action plan to reduce injuries and deaths on city streets. Vision Zero is a multi-agency effort, incorporating road engineering, traffic enforcement, community outreach and education, and policy work to make NYC streets safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector-borne Disease</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/vector-borne-disease/</guid>
      <description>Vectorborne diseasesare diseases that are transmitted from an arthropod (usually a tick or mosquito, etc.) to humans or other animals. Some vectorborne disease agents are maintained primarily through transmission between arthropods and humans (e.g., dengue virus and malaria), while others are maintained between arthropods and animal reservoirs (e.g., Lyme disease and West Nile virus) and humans may become infected incidentally.
Vectorborne Disease and the Environment Climate is one of many important interacting variables that affect people’s risk for vectorborne diseases in New York City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/violence/</guid>
      <description>Violence is the use of physical, verbal, and/or emotional force to injure, harm, abuse, damage, or destroy. Interpersonal violence includes child abuse and neglect, youth violence, intimate partner violence, sexual violence, and elder abuse. Violence can involve injury to self, including self-harm, suicide attempts, and death by suicide. Violence can also take the form of power against a group or community.
Violence is a public health issue because it is a cause of morbidity and mortality, leading to physical and emotional harm, an increase in negative health outcomes, premature death, psychological trauma and persistent fear to individuals and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather-Related Illness</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worker Health</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/worker-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-explorer/worker-health/</guid>
      <description>Every year in New York City, workers are injured on the job or become ill as a result of exposure to health hazards at work. However, most work-related illnesses and injuries are preventable – safer work environments can be achieved when workplace hazards are understood and appropriate prevention measures are put in place.
Data on work-related injuries and illness are used to show how often these preventable events occur and to identify factors that place workers at risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why violence is a public health issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/violence/</guid>
      <description>Using public health to prevent violence Experiencing violence affects people in many ways. It not only causes physical injury or death, but being exposed to it can also cause emotional and psychological trauma. Violence doesn’t just affect the immediate victim, it affects their surrounding community, too.
Violence can affect people throughout their lives: it is associated with worse birth outcomes, childhood developmental delays, physical and mental illness, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health, housing, and history</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:07:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/housing/</guid>
      <description>For health, place matters What determines whether or not you’re healthy? You may think about what you eat, whether you exercise, whether you smoke and your family medical history.
But you may not think about how your home affects your health - and you may not think about the factors that influence where you live. For a home to be healthy, it should be free of:  Cracks Holes Leaks Smoke Pests Old, peeling paint  In other words, a healthy home is a well-maintained home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environments matter: the road to street safety in NYC</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 10:54:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/streets/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 public health emergency has changed New York City in many ways - including how we get around the city. As the city continues to adapt to COVID-19, New Yorkers will look for ways to get around that feel safe - redistributing transit among different modes to ease crowding and increase safety on public transportation. As more New Yorkers use bicycles, let&#39;s take a look at safety on our streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting New Yorkers from extreme heat</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 08:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/heat/</guid>
      <description>Hot weather is dangerous. In New York City and across the country, more people on average die from extreme heat each year than from all other natural disasters.
Heat stress happens when your body’s temperature increases quickly. When the body can no longer control its temperature or cool itself down, it can lead to death.
At the NYC Health Department, we track heat stress deaths by reviewing causes of death recorded by the Bureau of Vital Statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disparities in violence</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/assaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 08:29:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/assaults/</guid>
      <description>Violence has profound effects. An assault, a shooting, a homicide, or any use of force affects people in many deep ways.
Violence causes physical and emotional harm. It can inflict fear, a constant sense of unease. It can cause short- and long-term trauma. Violence can affect people throughout their lives - including their health. It can lead to poor birth outcomes, compromised childhood development, negative health behaviors, physical and mental illness, and premature deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why asthma is a social justice issue</title>
      <link>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/povasthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 08:18:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nycehs.github.io/ehs-data-portal-frontend-temp/data-stories/povasthma/</guid>
      <description>Poverty affects health in many ways. In New York City, the story of asthma clearly illustrates this connection.
To understand the connection between poverty and asthma, take a look at this map of poverty rates in New York City, below. The darker the color, the more residents living in poverty.
  !function () { &#34;use strict&#34;; window.addEventListener(&#34;message&#34;, function (a) { if (void 0 !== a.data[&#34;datawrapper-height&#34;]) for (var e in a.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
