<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</title>
    <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social on Environment &amp; Health Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/keywords/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asthma triggers at home</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/asthma-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/asthma-triggers/</guid>
      <description>Housing conditions can trigger asthma. In New York City, childhood asthma is a significant health threat that affects thousands of children per year.&#xA;No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic conditions</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/economic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities Access to these are shaped by local, national and global distribution of resources and power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing maintenance</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/housing-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/housing-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>Buildings with maintenance issues and disrepair can harm health. Across NYC, low-income neighborhoods have a higher percentage of buildings in disrepair due to past and present disinvestment and housing discrimination. This housing disrepair harms residents&amp;rsquo; health.&#xA;No family should have to choose between affordable and healthy housing. All tenants are entitled to safe, decent and sanitary housing, which prevents disease and injury. All building owners are required by law to provide essential services such as heat and hot water, make timely repairs, and maintain a pest-free building.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing safety</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/housing-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/housing-safety/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health - both in terms of safety characteristics within the home, and in terms of factors that affect housing stability.&#xA;Safety characteristics A home&amp;rsquo;s safety characteristics might include:&#xA;Air conditioning, which is a vital tool to protect people who are at risk of heat-related illness and death Electric medical equipment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing stability</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/housing-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/housing-stability/</guid>
      <description>Most people spend most of their time in their home. That makes the home a crucial environment that can affect one&amp;rsquo;s health.&#xA;Housing stability In NYC, about one out of every three homes is owned by the person living there - about half the national average. Owning a home is a powerful way to build intergenerational wealth, but historical and contemporary disinvestment and housing discrimination has made it hard for many New Yorkers to own homes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social conditions</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/social-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/social-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Social and economic conditions affect people’s health. These conditions (also called “social determinants of health”) are conditions that people may be born into or fall into over the course of their lives.&#xA;People tend to be healthier when they have access to:&#xA;Economic and financial stability Higher education Adequate health care Healthy neighborhoods and safe, strong communities But when people don’t have access to these conditions, they experience worse health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/violence/</guid>
      <description>Violence is the use of physical, verbal, and/or emotional force to injure, harm, abuse, damage, or destroy. Interpersonal violence includes child abuse and neglect, youth violence, intimate partner violence, sexual violence, and elder abuse. Violence can involve injury to self, including self-harm, suicide attempts, and death by suicide. Violence can also take the form of power against a group or community.&#xA;Violence is a public health issue because it is a cause of morbidity and mortality, leading to physical and emotional harm, an increase in negative health outcomes, premature death, psychological trauma and persistent fear to individuals and communities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weather-related illness</title>
      <link>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gcappbesp307.health.dohmh.nycnet/dev-prod/data-explorer/weather-related-illness/</guid>
      <description>A region&amp;rsquo;s climate is characterized by its usual weather conditions, seasons, and patterns in extreme weather events such as heat waves, droughts, and hurricanes. New York City (NYC) faces public health risks from extreme weather events such as heat waves and coastal storms. With climate change, the severity of some of these risks will increase. A 2013 New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) report predicts that by the 2020s, average summer temperatures in New York City will increase by 2.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
